Help!
Me house is on fire!
Call the fire brigade!
Don't worry. Come along.
Hurry up. Hurry up.
Well done, lads!
Fill 'em up!
Pass the buckets!
There must be another way
of doing the credits.
That's right!
Every time they make
a Robin Hood movie,
they burn our village down.
Leave us alone,
Mel Brooks!
Yeah.
Yo, yo, yo!
Check it out.
Prince John and the sheriff
They was runnin' the show
Raisin' the taxes
'cause they needed the dough
A reign of terror
took over the land
They were
shakin' down the people
just to beat the band
I said hey
Hey
I said
Hey, nonny, nonny
and a ho-ho-ho
The people were unhappy
Morale was low
They had no place to turn to
There was nowhere to go
They needed a hero
but no one could be found
'Cause Robin Hood
was out of town
I said hey
Hey
I said
Hey, nonny, nonny
and a ho-ho-ho
He was put into the slammer
by his Arab foe
And in a little while
he would be no more
I said hey
- Hey
- I said hey
Hey
I said
Hey, nonny, nonny
and a whoa, whoa, whoa
Check it out
Ow!
Ah, hello, hello!
Welcome, welcome
to le dungeon!
Hello, I'm Falafel,
maître d' dungeon.
Please allow me to show you
to your cell. Come.
Duck.
I always forget
about that.
I'm so sorry,
but we cannot seat you
without the proper attire.
- See?
-
Irving.
Help me.
Ah!
That's much better.
And now I leave you
in the capable hands
of Muktar.
He's our head guard.
Please, it's better
you cooperate with him.
He's a tough guy.
And if there’s anything
you require, please don't
hesitate to scream.
Coming!
We're so busy!
Follow me!
Please sit.
Robin of Loxley,
where is your king?
King? King?
And which king
might that be?
King Richard, King Louis,
King Kong?
Larry King?
Impertinent English dog!
You shall talk.
I don't think so.
Chuchim, please,
the tongue looseners.
Speak, you dog.
Speak!
Uh-uh.
Ooh!
What did he say?
You don't wanna know.
You very brave
for a not-at-homeboy.
Oh, thank you.
I've been in this place
for a while. Perhaps I can
be of some service to you.
- Do you have any questions?
- What are you in for?
-Jaywalking.
- Oh. I see.
It's not gonna be easy
getting out of here.
What we need
is a great feat
of strength.
Feat of strength?
Au contraire!
Now that you are here
with me, what we have
is great strength of feet!
- Don't follow.
- Do as I do.
Put your feet on the bar,
both feet.
Now, on the count
of kick—
Kick!
Ha-ha!
- What was that noise?
- Uh, noise? Noise?
Uh— Uh, uh, uh, uh-
The noise you heard
was the breaking
of this poor man's heart.
Yes, that's it!
Ohh!
- What?
- He's decided to save his
life by betraying his king.
- Tsk, tsk, tsk.
- Oh, yes, that's it.
Oh, damn my eyes.
So go. Go tell your superiors
before he changes his mind.
Oh, by the love of Allah,
this is a wonderful thing!
Go.
It will mean
a big promotion for me.
Go!
Good news
is always rewarded!
Please go.
- On the other hand-
-
bad news
is severely punished.
Aah!
Now is our chance.
Quick, follow me!
You get that chain,
I'll get this one.
Righto!
We're free!
We're going home!
Move out of the way!
Come on.
Take my hand.
All right,
on the count of three!
One, two, three!
I just told them
the good news, and-
and-
and I'm in deep shit.
It is a very long journey
from Africa to England,
my friend.
Well.
I owe you a great debt
of gratitude, my friend.
I am called
Robin of Loxley.
My name is Asneeze,
father of Ahchoo.
Bless you.
No, no, no, no, no.
Ahchoo is my son.
He's in England,
your country.
He's an exchange student.
I'd like you
to look after him.
He's in need of guidance.
He is headstrong and cocksure.
Or is it
the other way around?
Say no more.
I vow on the sacred word
of Loxley,
I give you
my undying pledge,
my solemn oath...
on my father's honor,
on the blood of my heart,
on the word of my soul-
Good.
on the very
center of my being,
that nothing shall—
You must go now,
or you will miss the tide.
Yes, yes.
Well, farewell,
my friend.
And not to worry.
I'll find Ahchoo.
Good-bye, my friend.
Farewell.
Safe journey!
Home! Home!
England! Ahh!
Mmm! Mwah!
Oh, a horse. A horse.
My kingdom for a horse.
Get him!
Hold him.
Ahchoo?
Bless you!
Man, I hope someone's getting
a video of this thing.
- Damn!
-
That must be him.
Watch my back!
Your back just
got punched twice.
Thank you.
Hey, thanks, man.
You're welcome.
Who are you anyway?
I think now is not the time
for introductions.
Time out!
Excuse me, bad guys.
I am running out of air.
Gotta get pumped.
Huh?
Okay, honkies.
Time in!
By the by, do you know
praying mantis?
You're looking at him.
Let's get out of here!
Yeah, boy!
Go ahead, punk!
They're witches!
They're mad!
They're possessed!
They're crazy!
Good work.
Thanks, man.
You haven't seen
the last of us!
You've seen the last of us.
There she is, Loxley Hall,
home of my family
for seven generations.
Let's go!
Move it!
Come on. Let's go!
That's it, boys.
Let's go. Move it.
That's it!
Keep it going!
Yes, come on, come on.
Move it, move it.
Here we go.
Stop the castle!
You there!
I demand to know what
is going on here!
Read it and weep.
Hey, what up
with that?
"Hear ye, hear ye.
"For failure
to pay back taxes,
"all the lands,
castle and properties
of the family of Loxley...
"shall be taken
in lieu of payment.
Signed, Prince John's
royal accountant,
H.M.R. Blockhead"?
This is a sham!
I vow here and now
I will restore my castle
to its rightful place.
Yeah, yeah.
You vow, we move!
Let's go, boys!
Take it out!
So long!
Move it!
Keep it going!
Come on!
That's a boy!
Blinkin?
Who's that?
It's Blinkin.
Our family's
loyal, blind servant.
I gotta get
the horse, man.
Good.
Blinkin!
Uh, be right out.
Master Robin,
is that you?
Yes!
Back from
the Crusades?
Yes!
And alive?
Yes.
Oh, happy day!
I'm quite sure
there was a door there.
Master Robin!
You lost your arms
in battle.
How— How terrible!
But you grew
some nice boobs.
Blinkin, I'm over here.
Oh. Uh, later.
Blinkin, listen to me.
They've taken the castle.
I thought it felt
a bit drafty.
Ohh!
This never would have happened
if your father was alive.
He's dead?
Yes.
And my mother?
She died of pneumonia
whilst—
Oh, you were away!
My brothers?
They were all killed
by the plague.
My dog Pongo?
Run over by a carriage.
My goldfish Goldy?
Eaten by the cat.
My cat?
Choked on the goldfish.
Oh, it's good to be home,
ain't it, Master Robin?
Oh! Oooh!
Wait a minute.
What is that?
Oh, your father wanted me
to give you this.
He said that inside
is the key...
to the greatest treasure
in all the land.
Ohh.
May I keep it?
Um, no, Blinkin.
I think I ought to honor
my father's wishes.
Of course.
Come, Blinkin.
Let us leave this
depressing foundation.
We have much to do
and less time to do it in.
Yes.
Hey. Hey, Robin,
wait up.
Oh, well done, Ahchoo.
Yeah, he was running fast,
but I caught his ass.
Who's that?
Blinkin, I'd like you
to meet Ahchoo.
A Jew? Here?
No, no.
Not a Jew. Ahchoo.
Hey, put it there.
How do you do?
I've been better.
- What is that?
- Help me! Help me!
Aah, save me!
Save me!
Looks like a runaway
white boy.
All right. Steady on.
What's the matter?
They're after me.
Who is?
Over that boy hand!
Hand over that boy.
Who demands it?
The sheriff
of Rottingham.
And what
has the boy done?
He was caught poaching
in the king's forest.
He "deered"
to kill a king's dare.
Dared to kill a king's deer.
And this
is an offense?
One punishable by death.
Where have you been?
Fighting with King Richard
in the Crusades.
Unfortunately,
my father couldn't get me
into the National Guard.
Whoa-oh!
How dare you talk to me
in that fashion?
Who are you?
I am Robin of Loxley.
Oh, yes, yes,
I've heard of you.
They say you're pretty handy
with a sword.
Let's find out!
I was angry at you
before, Loxley,
but now I'm really
pissed off!
Pissed off?
If I was that close
to a horse's wiener,
I'd be worried about
getting pissed on.
You know, this wasn't
a very smart thing for you
to have done, Loxley.
I'll pay for this!
You'll pay for this!
Kill them!
Wait, I've...
changed my mind.
Wise decision.
So, until we meet again,
have a safe journey.
Ooh! Ooh! Ow!
Oh! Ah!
Mind the big rocks!
Shut up, you bloody fools!
Good riddance
to bad rubbish.
Oh, thank you
for saving me life,
milord.
I shall tell all that I see
that there is one man
in England...
who's not afraid to
stand up to Rottingham
and his men.
Good. Tell them that.
And tell them also
that I vow to put an end
to the injustice,
right the wrongs,
end the tyranny,
restore the throne,
protect the forest,
introduce folk dancing,
demand a four-day
work week...
and affordable health care
for Saxons and Normans.
Yes, yes. Good, good.
Well, it's getting dark.
I gotta go home
alone now.
Right, right.
Good-bye.
What an unusual child.
Hmm.
Where is the one
That I love most of all
When will I hear him call
Marian, Marian
He is the one
Who can make my life whole
Joyful forevermore
I've waited so patiently
For a true love
When will he come for me
Where is he
Where is he, oh
Where is the man
Who carries the key
When will he be
With his Marian
Marian
I cannot wait
Till he sets my heart free
Oh, when will I know him
When will I see him
When will I hear him
Say Marian
My love
Oh!
Hurry up, mein lady!
You better get out
of that tub...
before that thing
begins to rust.
All right, Broomhilde.
Hurry, hurry.
It's freezing.
Button up.
You're going to catch
your death of cold.
Oh, these castles
are so drafty.
Toasty warm.
Oh, Broomhilde, look.
A happy little bluebird.
Hello.
Ah. This means
I must make a wish.
I hope against hope,
I wish against wish...
that the heavens bring me
a kind, wonderful, gentle man...
who possesses the key
to my...
heart.
Good-bye,
my little friend.
Ooh, that happy
little bluebird...
has left a happy
little doo-doo on your hand.
Prince John,
I must speak with you.
All right, everybody.
Later, later.
See you later.
Oh!
Sire.
I have news.
What sort of news
do you have?
Not bad news, is it?
You know I can't take
bad news.
The day started out so good.
Had a good night's sleep.
Had a good B.M.
I don't want to hear
any bad news.
Now, what type
of news is it?
Well, to be perfectly frank,
it's bad!
I knew it!
I knew it was bad news!
Wait a minute.
I have an idea.
Maybe if you tell me
the bad news in a good way,
it won't sound so bad.
The bad— The bad news
in a good way?
Yes, I can do that.
Bad news in a good way.
Um— Well, here goes.
Wait till you hear this.
I just bumped into
Robin of Loxley.
He's back from the Crusades.
You know,
he just beat the crap
out of me and my men.
He— He hates you,
and he loves
your brother Richard.
And-
he wants to
see you hanged!
You-
We're— We're—
We're in an awful lot
of trouble!
What, are you crazy?
Why are you laughing?
This is terrible news!
Well, I-I-
You-You told me-
I was just trying
to soften the blow.
Well, you blew it.
This is a knotty problem,
sire, not easily solved.
Yes, you're right.
What to do?
Got it! Latrine!
The weird creature
in the tower, the one
who protects my future.
The weird creature
in the tower, the one
who protects my future.
Oh, yes, Latrine.
Is she ugly!
Latrine? Latrine,
where are you?
I must talk with you!
Latrine! Latrine!
No!
Oh, it's you.
There's a new threat
to my power.
What can you tell me
about Robin of Loxley?
Robin of Loxley?
Robin of Loxley.
Let me see.
Raven's egg,
blood of a hen!
Little bit more blood,
yes.
Eyeballs of a crocodile.
Testicles of a newt.
I guess he's
a transsexual now!
Yeah. Ugh.
Yes.
Mmm!
Robin of Loxley
is handsome and brave.
He seeks to regain
his family's honor.
The little sod
could be trouble.
Are you certain?
Certain?
You want certain,
hire yourself a witch.
I'm just your cook.
Here. Eat this.
Hmm, looks fabulous.
Looks like a seder
at Vincent Price's house.
Such an unusual name, Latrine.
How did your family
come by it?
We changed it
in the ninth century.
You mean,
you changed it...
to Latrine?
Yeah.
Used to be Shithouse.
It's a good change.
Now, what about
this Robin fellow, huh?
How can I stop him?
Maybe I could devise...
a magic potion,
one that would make him
unable to perform
the slightest task.
But in return,
you must help me.
What, are you kidding?
Name it. Anything you want.
Put in a good word
for me with the sheriff
of Rottingham.
I've got the hots for him.
Hmm.
I keep a likeness of him
in my boudoir.
Oh. Ohh!
Oh! Oh, Rotty!
Rotty, Rotty, Rotty!
I am amazed,
to think that a handsome
blade like the sheriff
of Rottingham...
would ever want
a creature like you.
Well, if you’re gonna
puncture my dreams,
you can forget about
my promise to help you.
No, wait, wait, wait.
Wait, wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait, wait, wait!
Wait.
Maybe if we
got him drunk.
Very drunk.
You got a shot.
Ooh, good!
Whoa.
Dismount.
Wait here.
I'll go make sure
it's safe.
I say, would you mind,
um, awfully,
getting out of the way?
I say, not until
you pay the toll.
Toll? What toll?
Well, the toll you pay
for crossing me bridge.
I'm not paying
any toll.
This bridge is
on my family's land.
Well, it used to be
my family's land.
Hey. Hey, you're—
you're Robin of Loxley!
Hey!
Yeah!
And who might you be?
Oh, they call me
Little John.
Uh, but don't let
my name fool you.
In real life,
I'm very big.
I'll take your word for it.
Now let me pass.
Uh- No.
Sorry,
but a toll is a toll,
and a roll is a roll,
and if we don't get no tolls,
then we don't eat no rolls.
I made that up.
It's very fascinating.
I'm afraid I'm going
to have to hurt you.
Oh, yeah. My pleasure.
Will!
Thank you.
Hey, Blinkin.
Did you say,
"Abe Lincoln"?
No, I ain't
say Abe Lincoln!
I said, "Hey, Blinkin."
Hold the reins, man.
Damn.
Hey, Robin, Robin.
Excuse me.
No, excuse me.
Hey, look, man.
You don't have to do this.
Look, this ain't exactly
the Mississippi.
I'm on one side, see?
I'm on the other side.
I'm on the east bank.
I'm on the west bank.
It is not that critical.
Not the point.
It's the principle
of the thing.
Yeah.
Nice knowing you.
Aah!
Ow.
Ow!
Uh! Ho!
Help me!
I can't swim!
I'm drowning!
Oh, no, I'm drowning!
Help me!
Help me! Help me!
Oh, God! Oh, I'm drowning!
I'm drowning, I'm drowning,
I'm drowning!
There, there.
You're all right now.
Thank you, Robin.
You saved me life.
What?
Air!
Sorry.
There.
I'm in your debit.
Think nothing of it.
Hey, are y'all
all right?
Huh. Let me introduce you
to my friends.
That is Blinkin.
And this is Ahchoo.
Bless ya.
That's my name, man.
Ahchoo.
Here, let me introduce you
to my best friend,
Will Scarlet.
Scarlet's my middle name.
My full name is
Will Scarlet O'Hara.
We're from Georgia.
He's deadly
with his daggers.
Really? How's about
a demonstration?
Gladly.
All right then.
Fire an arrow
straight at my heart.
- Are you serious?
- Absolutely.
Okay. Good-bye.
Hey, what part of Georgia
are you from?
South Central?
Well, I haven't quite
figured that part out yet.
I see.
I'm sorry 'bout
the toll thing, Robin.
I mean,
it's Prince John.
He's taken our homes
and everything we own.
We've nothin' left.
Not to worry,
Little John.
Even as we speak, I'm forming
a plan to make trouble for
Prince John and Rottingham.
Tonight,
I'll crash their party
and serve warning...
that there are those who
will fight to rid England
of their tyranny.
Good! We'll join you!
Yeah!
No, no, no, no.
I can't risk the lives
of others.
One man can
get in more easily
than half a dozen.
Well, I must be off.
Fare thee well.
I'll see thee
upon my return.
All right, man.
Peace, bro.
Take it easy.
Thanks.
Man, white men can’t jump.
Ah. Here you are, son.
Your ticket, sir.
Kill him!
No, wait.
You know, a mime...
is a terrible thing
to waste.
Let him go.
Lovely Bristols.
Good evening, milady.
Milady.
Maid Marian, you know
our good sheriff
of Rottingham.
You look ravishing,
my dear.
Please allow me
to help you to your seat.
Mmm.
I must say that Prince John
has spared no expense
for tonight's party.
We have exotic foods
from across the seas.
Coconuts, bananas
and dates.
Would you care
for a date?
Yes, thank you.
How 'bout
next Thursday?
Good evening.
That's-
That's him!
That's Loxley!
Greetings, Your Highness.
Traif.
A present for you
and your guests.
That's a wild boar.
No, no, that's a wild pig.
That's a wild bore.
Funny!
Very amusing.
So you're Robin
of Loxley, huh?
I've heard so much
about you.
- And you are?
- Maid Marian.
Ah, Maid Marian.
Rumors of your beauty
have traveled
far and wide,
yet I see they hardly
do you justice.
Oh!
Quite a smoothy.
He's definitely a smoothy.
Enough!
King illegal forest...
to pig wild kill
in it a is!
What?
I mean, don't you know
it is illegal
to kill a wild pig...
in the king's forest?
Is it not also illegal
to sit in the king's throne
and usurp his power...
in his absence?
Careful, Robin.
You go too far.
I've only just begun.
I've come to warn you
that if you do not stop
levying these evil taxes,
I shall lead
the good people of England
in a revolt against you.
And why should the people
listen to you?
Because, unlike
some other Robin Hoods,
I can speak
with an English accent.
Oh!
To tell you the truth,
this guy is starting
to get on my nerves!
Worry not, Your Highness.
I shall dispose
of this feathered upstart.
I challenge you
to a duel.
I accept.
Whoa!
That's going to cost you,
Loxley.
Please,
put it on my bill.
So it's come down
to this, has it?
A fight to the death.
Mano a mano,
man to man,
just you and me...
and my guards!
Ooh!
Check, please.
Table one.
Ha!
-
Uh. Ooh. Ah.
Hurry, let's
get out of here!
Oh.
Uhh.
Refreshment, sir.
Ah, thank you, Blinkin.
Sounds like
we're winning, sir.
Indeed, we are.
Carry on.
Right you are.
Save me, save me.
Hurt them, hurt them!
Yes, save them, save them.
Hurt you, hurt you.
I've got it.
- Ohh!
-
Care for some dessert?
One, two, three!
Fire!
Maid Marian!
Do you believe in...
love at first sight?
Depends on what
you're looking at.
Well?
Yes! Yes! Yes!
Where is she?
Ohh!
To be continued.
Mein liebchen,
I'm so glad I found you.
Come on. This party's
getting rough.
Hyah!
Am I good? I'm good.
Bar the doors!
Don't let them get away.
Surround the great hall.
Now you're talkin'.
Shut the door.
I hope it's worth
the noise!
We've got him.
Aha! Right rope.
Oh!
Look at this.
We went from royalty
to recycling.
Little John,
would you get the door?
Yeah, I'll try.
Well, it's been
a wonderful party,
and we'd love to stay
and all that, but, um,
I'm afraid we really
must dash, so ta-ta.
No, no, no.
I sent word
throughout England
that each village...
should send
the very best men
they have.
These are them.
Hmm, we're in
a lot of trouble.
Good people who have traveled
from villages near and far,
lend me your ears.
That's disgusting.
Hear me!
Men the likes of Prince John
and Rottingham must be stopped.
Stopped from taxing us into
poverty, from taking from us
what is rightfully ours.
If we stand up to them,
all together as one,
we can win the day!
We shall go on to the end.
We shall not flag or fail.
We shall fight
on the seas and oceans.
We shall defend our isle,
whatever the cost may be.
We shall never surrender.
Then they shall
say of us,
"Never have so many...
owed so much to so few."
That was beautiful.
What's going on?
They're asleep.
Hey, man.
Tough room.
Why don't you let me
give it a try?
Okay.
- Look at yourselves!
-
Go ahead.
Take a look around.
- Oh, people of Sherwood,
you been had!
-  Yeah!
Hoodwinked!
Yeah!
Bamboozled!
Run amok.
We didn't land
on Sherwood Forest.
Sherwood Forest
landed on us!
Yeah!
Very good.
They're all warmed up.
Brother Ahchoo is right.
And I say we fight back!
Yeah!
Yes.
- Are you with me,
yea or nay?
- Which one means yes?
- Yea.
-  Yea!
Men, grab your uniforms
and equipment...
and prepare for
the training sequence.
All right, gentlemen,
grab your feathered caps,
jerkins, bodkins,
boots, swords,
quivers...
and panty hose.
Now, men, the object
of this exercise...
is to hit the target.
All right?
Oh!
Hmm!
Now, men, I want you
to keep your eye on Will...
and do exactly
as he does.
Ah-ooh!
Yeah!
Very good.
Well done, Will.
Right!
All right, Will!
That's not so hard.
We could do that.
Piece of cake.
Good boy.
Ready, men?
Charge!
Oh, man.
Hey, Rob, man,
maybe we should take
the dummies into battle.
Ha!
Hmm.
Sire?
I must speak with you.
What are you smelling?
These aren't my bubbles.
They're from the pipes.
Your Majesty,
I have terrible news.
What?
"Strucky"
has "loxed" again.
What?
Loxley has struck again.
I'm gonna need privacy,
so you guys can blow.
Not blow. Blow!
I'm so depressed.
Your Majesty, come with me,
and I will show you something
that will make you very happy.
Fetch the royal robe!
Your Majesty?
Stop me if I'm wrong
about this, but...
wasn't your mole...
on the other side?
I have a mole?
What is it?
It's what we've named
a stealth catapult.
We've been working on it
secretly for months.
It can hurl one
of these heavy boulders,
undetected,
over a hundred yards,
completely destroying
anything it hits.
Wow!
How does it work?
It's quite simple.
You just take one of these
heavy rocks, put it here
where I'm sitting,
and then pull
on that lever.
You mean, like this?
Oh, Dear Lord,
if you see fit to send me
my one true love—
Thank you!
Oh, my God!
Here! Let me work
my magic on you!
Oh, oh, oh, oh!
No, no!
I've got a headache.
Where are you going?
Oh, bugger!
I was that close.
I touched it.
I don't like the way
you're walking.
You've been into
the sacramental wine again.
You're farshnoshket!
You drunken mule, you.
Whoa, Morris, whoa.
Halt there, friend.
You’ve just entered
the territory of Robin Hood
and his Merry Men.
- Faigelehs?
-  No!
No, no, no, no.
We're straight,
just merry.
Azoy?
And who might you be,
with the exceptionally long
feather in your hat?
I am Robin of Loxley.
Robin of Loxley?
I've just come
from Maid Marian,
the lady whose heart you stole,
you prince of thieves, you.
I knew her mother and father
before they were taken
in the plague.
Lord and Lady Bagelle.
You were meant
for each other,
you and Maid Marian.
What a combination!
Loxley and Bagelle.
You can't miss.
And who are you, sir?
I am Rabbi Tuckman,
purveyor
of sacramental wine...
and mohel extraordinaire.
- Hello, Rabbi.
- Hello, boys.
Mohel. Don't believe
I've ever heard
of that profession.
Mohel?
He's a very important guy.
He makes circumcisions.
What, pray tell, sir,
is a circumcision?
Oh, it's the latest rage.
The ladies love it.
I want one!
I'll take two.
Put me down too.
I'm getting one.
I'm game.
How's it done?
It's a snap.
I take my little machine.
I take your
little thing, see?
I put it into
this little hole here,
and... nip the tip!
Ow!
- Who's first?
- I changed me mind.
I forgot, man.
I already got one.
Christian.
I gotta work with
a much younger crowd.
Rabbi, you seem to be
on the side of good.
Will you join us
and share with us
some of your wisdom,
some of your counsel,
and, uh, perhaps...
some of your wine?
Wisdom and counsel,
that's easy.
But this is sacramental wine.
It's only used to bless things.
Wait a minute!
There's things here-
there's trees,
there's rocks,
there's birds,
there's squirrels.
Come on!
We'll bless them all
until we get farshnoshket!
-Join me!
-
Let's hear it
for the rabbi!
Good evening,
Don Giovanni.
Yeah.
Buona sera.
Yes. It was, uh,
very good of you to come
at such short notice.
Well.
And all the way
from Jersey.
Well, it is
quite a drive.
Yes, but you do realize that
Prince John expressly commanded
this to be a secret meeting?
I mean,
who are these men?
These are
my trusted associates.
On my right,
Dirty Ezio.
On my left,
Filthy Luca.
Now.
We thank you
for inviting us...
on the day
of your daughter's wedding.
No, no.
I hope her first child
is a masculine child.
Shut up. We didn't
even have our meeting yet.
Oh, yeah.
All right.
I understand that you have
been bothered by this fruit,
Robin Hood.
That you want Robin
rubbed out,
eliminated,
maybe even killed.
Yes.
You put it succinctly.
Suck what?
Succinctly.
It means perfectly.
Oh, yeah.
Well, I knew that.
Excuse me, Don Giovanni.
Your lizard seems limp.
At my age, you know,
sometimes-
Oh, oh, my lizard.
Oh! No.
Nah, he’s just sleeping.
Charlie.
Charlie. Oh, Charlie.
Charlie, I could've been
somebody. I could have been
a contender.
You know, Charlie's—
Charlie's got bad breath.
Oh! He got excited,
you know.
Come over here, Ezio.
Uh— Mmm, no.
Now, normally
I would be so happy
to be of service to you,
but there is something
that weighs very heavily
on my heart.
In the years
that we have been friends,
England and Jersey,
never once have you
invited me to your home
for coffee and cake...
or ganool, something,
you know.
A "guh-what"?
A ganool.
It's a pastry
with stuffing.
And it's got sprinkles
on it. Mmm.
Excuse me.
I don't understand
a word you're saying.
I just came back
from the dentist,
and they left in
the cotton balls.
I will take these cotton balls
from you with my hand...
and put them in my pocket.
Yeah. Whatever.
You know, your other associate
says very little.
Well, my other associate
says nothing.
Why is that?
Because my enemy
cut out his tongue.
Good grief!
Why?
Well, 'cause he went
like this.
And he didn't like it,
so he cut out his tongue.
Come over here.
Go like this.
He can't do it.
I love to tease him!
Tell me, Don Giovanni.
Yeah, that's me.
What?
What do you intend to do
about Robin Hood?
Listen to this.
I got an idea.
Tomorrow— Tomorrow you're
gonna have your medieval
fun and games.
You'll make
the most important event
the archery contest.
Robin will not be able
to resist.
Why is that?
We'll make him an offer
he can't refuse.
I was just gonna say that.
That's brilliant!
Thank you.
But-
What?
You do realize that Robin
is the finest archer
in the land?
Oh, no.
Don't you understand?
Luca is good,
better, best.
Show him
your archery medals.
Ta-da!
Wowee!
See? I couldn't
have said it better myself.
Now, Luca beats Robin
at the archery contest,
and then Dirty Ezio
makes Robin no more.
No more?
All right, you want
plain English?
Robin is gonna be dead.
D-E-D. Dead.
You hear him?
Broomhilde?
Broomhilde, wake up!
There's a foul plot afoot.
It's not mine feet.
I just washed them.
No, no, no.
Prince John and the sheriff
have hired men to kill Robin.
We must warn him
immediately!
Wait, mein lady!
If Prince John should see us-
You're right.
We'll go out the back.
Right.
Lady!
Broomhilde,
I'm going on ahead.
Catch me up.
Come on, Lady.
Farfelkugel!
Ooh.
Farfelkugel.
If I was you,
I would never
do that again.
Any questions?
Good.
Forward!
Blinkin, what are you
doing up there?
Guessing.
I...
guess no one's coming.
Please come down from there.
Twit.
Well, I guess there's a ladder
around here somewhere.
Oh. Here we are.
Right.
Oh, shit.
I can see!
No, I was wrong.
Blimey, these are
hard to get on.
Let's face it.
You gotta be a man
to wear tights.
Will, how are me seams?
Perfect.
Every time.
We're men
We're men in tights
We roam around the forest
looking for fights
We're men
We're men in tights
We rob from the rich
and give to the poor
That's right!
We may look like sissies
But watch what you say
or else we'll put out
your lights
We're men
We're men in tights
Always on guard defending
the people's rights
La, la, la, la, la, la
la, la, la
la, la, la, la
La, la, la, la, la
We're men
Manly men!
We're men in tights
Yes!
We roam around the forest
looking for fights
We're men
We're men in tights
We rob from the rich
and give to the poor
That's right!
We may look like pansies
But don't get us wrong
or else we'll put out
your lights
We're men
we're men in tights
Tight tights!
Always on guard defending
the people's rights
When you're in a fix
just call for the men
in tights
We're butch!
Marian!
Here.
Allow me.
Oh, thank you.
You are so sweet.
Is there anything
I can do for you?
Yeah.
You can get off me.
-
- Little John!
I panicked.
Darling, what are you
doing here?
I have come to warn you.
Prince John and Rottingham
have hired murderers to kill
you at the fair tomorrow!
You mustn't go!
That's easy.
I won't.
Oh, I'm so happy.
They were going to try
to lure you there by having
an archery contest.
An archery contest?
Their archer
is unbeatable.
Really?
Robin, promise
you won't go.
All right.
I promise you won't go.
Thank you.
- Hey, wait a minute, Robin.
You said that—
- Cool it.
Chill.
Come, my dear.
The night is young,
and you're so beautiful.
B-flat.
The night is young
Haah!
And you're so beautiful
Here among the shadows
Beautiful lady
Open your heart
The scene is set
The breezes sing of it
Can't you get
into the swing of it
Lady
When do we start
- When the lady
is kissable
- Ooh
And the evening is cool
Ooh
Any dream is permissible
- In the heart of a fool
- Ooh
Oh.
The moon is high
And you're so glamorous
And if I seem
over-amorous
- Lady
- Ooh
What can I do
The night is young
And I'm in love
- With
-
You
Em, uh-
Oh, my dearest.
I'm ready for that kiss now.
But first
I must warn you.
It could only be a kiss,
for I am a virgin...
and could never...
go all the way.
But—
Unless, of course,
I were married.
Or if a man pledged
his endless love to me.
Yes-
Or if I knew that he
desperately cared for me,
or if he were really cute.
But, my darling,
you're shivering.
Are you cold?
What are you wearing
underneath that cape?
Practically nothing.
Ohh!
Oh, except that.
I forgot to tell you
about my chastity belt.
It's an Everlast.
I'll bet.
Oh, darling.
Don't despair.
For it was written
on a scroll,
"One day he
who is destined for me...
"shall be endowed
with the magical key...
that will bring
an end to my virginity."
Oh, Marian!
If only 'twere me.
Oh, if it 'twere you,
'twould be...
"twerrific."
Achtung! No ding-ding
without the wedding ring.
A-bup, bup, bup, bup, bup.
Good-bye, my dearest.
- A-bup, bup, bup.
- Toodle-oo.
Au revoir,
auf Wiedersehen, ciao.
Time out, time out.
What is wrong?
I should have never
worn these shoes!
They just don't
match my purse.
Blinkin,
fix your boobs.
What?
You look like
a bleeding Picasso.
Oh!
Goodness gracious.
Peanuts!
Peanut power here.
Hey, poor man's lunch there.
Hey, you. Shell game here.
The royal archery contest
is about to begin!
Archers,
take your places.
Are we... prepared?
Sire.
Hmm?
Oh, that's good.
That's good.
Archers to the line!
Ready.
Aim.
Wait for it.
Fire!
The two archers that hit
the bull's-eye can stay.
The rest of you gentlemen
can bugger off.
Granddad
won't like this.
There he is.
The old man
is Loxley.
Are you sure?
It looks like Mark Twain.
The old man
may go first.
Well done,
Robin of Loxley.
He's crazy.
We gotta stop him.
Sorry, ladies.
This is the royal entrance.
You'll have to go around
the other way.
Look what you've done.
You idiot!
Now he's even more of a hero
to the people.
Luca Pazzo
still has a shot.
But he hit the very center
of the bull's-eye, schmuck!
Wait and watch, sire.
He split Robin's arrow
in twain!
Things are looking up, huh?
Nice shot!
Oh, Robin's in trouble.
Come on!
Hey!
I lost. I lost?
Wait a minute.
I'm not supposed to lose.
Let me see the script.
Yo, Robin,
time to fly.
Go back to Sherwood Forest!
Oh, good.
They've opened
the salad bar.
Wait!
I get another shot!
He gets another shot!
Does Robin get
another shot?
Yes, he does. He does.
Squires and ladies,
silence. Listen.
Robin has another shot.
Let's give him
the chop!
Oh, oh-oh-oh-oh
Oh-oh-oh
Quick. Eliminate him
before he shoots.
Oh, oh-oh-oh-oh
Oh-oh-oh
How did you do that?
I heard that coming
a mile away.
Very good, Blinkin.
Well done.
Pardon? Who's talking?
"Patriot arrow"?
Yes!
Arrest him!
Move it, move it!
Out of the way!
Loxley is a traitor
to the crown!
It'll be so much fun
to watch you hang.
Wait.
What for?
If you promise not to kill
Robin, I shall do the most
disgusting thing...
that I can think of.
Mmm.
And what's that?
I shall marry you.
What?
You'll be mine?
You'll give yourself
to me every night?
And sometimes
right after lunch?
Yes. But only my body.
You can never have my heart,
my mind or my soul.
Oh. Oh, yes.
I respect that. Mm-hmm.
Marian, my life's
not worth it!
Just say nay!
Ha!
Walk this way.
-
- Send word to one and all
and all and one!
- That's a little redundant, isn't it?
- What?
Shut up! Tell everybody
that before the day is out,
we shall have a wedding...
or a hanging.
Either way we ought to have
a lot of fun, huh?
Man, we are
grossly outnumbered.
Yeah, so what
can we do?
We gotta get the villagers.
The villagers?
They're not ready to fight.
Man,
we are choiceless.
Blinkin, what's the fastest
way to reach the villagers?
Why don't we fox them!
Fox 'em.
Now, Mickey, take
this message to the village
as fast as you can.
Pay attention.
Have you got it?
Good.
Come on, y'all.
Let's get out this ladies'
clothing and into our tights.
Come on, man.
There you go.
Let's see. Are you about
a 16, 16 1/2, huh?
Ooh, ooh.
There.
It's a little tight.
Well, that's the idea.
Would you care
for a blindfold?
No. How about half a one?
A kiss, sir?
Sorry.
Good Morrow, Abbot.
Good Morrow.
Welcome, Abbot.
Hello, Abbot.
Good Morrow.
Hey, Abbot!
I hate that guy.
Ooh, she's beautiful.
Goodness!
Present swords!
What's going on?
Just in case
you change your mind,
my dear.
I will conduct
the opening prayer
in the New Latin.
O Ord-lay,
iveus-gay our-yay
essings-blay.
Amen-ay
We are gathered here
today...
to witness the marriage
of Mervyn, the sheriff of-
Mervyn?
Your name is Mervyn?
Shut up, shut up!
Continue with
the service!
Okay, Mervyn.
Do you,
Sheriff of Rottingham,
take Maid Marian of Bagelle
to be your lawful wedded wife,
to love and to hold
in sickness and in health...
till death do you part?
Yes! I do!
Get on with it!
Do you, Marian, vow to do
all the stuff I just said
to him?
Say "I do," or Robin dies.
I— I-
I— I—
I do... not!
-
- Oh!
Who's the man?
Go!
Arrest them!
Seize them!
Stop them!
Hurt them!
Look! The villagers
are coming!
Oh!
I believe this
belongs to you, sir.
Well, you know
what they say.
No noose is good noose.
Nice shooting,
Ahchoo.
Well, to tell you the truth,
I was aiming for the hangman.
Uh-oh, fellas.
We got company.
On the count of jump.
Wait for it.
Charge!
Jump.
Oh, yeah!
Ow.
I shall have you,
married or no.
Yeah!
The sheriff.
He got your woman, man.
He's takin' her
to the tower.
He gonna deflower her
in the tower. Ooh.
I'm sorry we don't have
enough time for romance,
my dear.
Consider this foreplay.
A chastity belt!
Ooh, that's going to chafe
my willy.
I'll be back.
Wha-
I hope she's still wearin'
her iron underwear.
Yeah.
No matter what you do,
I shall never
submi-i-i-it!
- Aha!
- Robi-i-i-in!
- Prepare for the fight scene.
-
Forgive the interruption,
my darling.
I'll dispatch your love
and then come back...
and finish the job.
En garde.
Thanks for the warning.
- Shocking!
-
Parry, parry,
thrust, thrust.
Good!
-
Hey!
Oh, sorry.
It is the key
to the greatest treasure
in all the land!
Oh! Robin, this means
you've always been
my one true love,
because it’s just
the right size.
It's not the size that counts!
It's how you use it!
Robin!
Aha! Ha, ha!
Ha, ha.
- Thank you, my friend.
-
- Aah.
Oh, it's not so bad.
I was wrong.
Oh, my dear beloved
sheriff of Rottingham!
You've been run through.
How do you feel?
I'm dying, you fool!
You don't have to die.
I don't?
No. I've got
this magic pill...
that could save
your life.
And I'll give it to you
if you promise to marry me...
and be mine forever.
Oh, all right.
Yes, yes.
How do you feel now?
Good, good.
Surprisingly good.
And yet, somehow...
incredibly depressed.
I always wanted
to marry a cop.
Wait, wait!
I've changed my mind!
I love you,
Robin of Loxley.
And I you,
Marian of Bagelle.
Oh!
Oh, my darling.
At last.
Yes, yes.
Yes, yes!
Yes!
No!
Wait, wait!
You're not married yet!
Before you do it,
you must go through it.
Or else I blew it.
Hey, Rabbi!
Who calls?
It is I, Robin.
We wish to get married
in a hurry!
Married in a hurry!
That's wonderful. Wait!
I'm on my last customer.
I'll be right out.
Put a little ice on it.
It'll be fine.
Ay, yi, yi!
Married in a hurry,
married in a hurry!
Please invite me to the bris.
Now, are you ready?
Robin, do you?
I do.
Marian, do you?
I now pronounce you
man and-
I object.
Who asked?
It's King Richard,
back from the Crusades!
Boy, now I'm in trouble.
You are no longer worthy
to wear...
this sacred symbol
of authority!
Oh, please have mercy
on me, Brother.
It wasn't my fault.
I got some really bad
advice from Rottingham.
Bullshit! Bullshit!
Brother,
you have surrounded
your given name...
with a foul stench.
From this day forth,
all the toilets
in this kingdom...
shall be known
as "johns."
No!
Take him away!
No. Wait, wait.
Put him
in the Tower of London.
Make him part of the tour.
Robin, the news
of your great deeds...
has reached me
even in Jerusalem.
England owes you and your men
a great debt of gratitude.
Henceforth, all your
family's rights and lands
shall be returned,
and you shall rule all Sherwood
from this day forth.
Kneel, Robin of Loxley.
And arise,
Sir Robin of Loxley.
Thank you, sir.
Excuse me, King.
Why, if you like this guy
so much, do you object
to his marrying Maid Marian?
I have no objections,
but I have not yet
kissed the bride.
It is a custom
and my royal right.
Hold this, Father.
Rabbi.
Whatever.
It's good to be the king.
Now you may marry them.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Here's your knife.
Sword.
Whatever.
Okay, where did we leave off?
Oh, that's right.
- We're up to the best part.
Do you, Marian?
- I do.
Do you, Robin?
I do.
I now pronounce you
man and...
wife.
We're going to have to
remodel the castle...
to make room
for all the babies.
For my first
order of business,
I wish to appoint
a new sheriff of Rottingham.
My friend, Ahchoo.
All right!
A black sheriff?
He's black?
And why not?
It worked in Blazing Saddles.
That's good.
Good-bye! Bye-bye! Bye-bye!
So that's the story
and it worked out good
King Richard's on his throne
and Robin's back in the hood
So let's bid our friends
a fond adieu
And hope we meet again
in Robin Hood II
I said hey
Hey
Hey, nonny, nonny, nonny
Here we go
Rise,
Sir Robin of Loxley.
Yeah. Buona sera.
Buona sera.
Hey, Abbot!
I hate that guy.
Let's see now, what are you,
16, 16 1/2?
Faigelehs?
Welcome home,
Mrs. Of Loxley.
Oh, I'm so happy.
Oh, my dearest.
Shall I...
turn the key?
Oh, yes, darling!
But please...
be gentle.
Um, darling.
What?
You're not going to
believe this.
What?
It won't open.
Wait. I have an idea.
Call the locksmith!
Where is the one
That I love most of all
When will I
hear him call
Marian, Marian
He is the one
Who can make my life full
Joyful
Forevermore
Hey
Ooh
Where is the maid
That I'm longing to see
Where can she be
My sweet Marian, Marian
Oh, when will I
Hold you here
in my arms
Knowing
You are my love
I waited so patiently
For a true love
When will he come for me
Where is he
In all my dreams
There's a vision I see
Your hand in mine
My dear Marian, Marian
There's no tomorrow
Without you, my love
Oh, you are my reason
To be
Oh
Hey
My heart has made a vow
It’s just for you
You are my one true love
Only you
Where is the man
Who carries the key
Please say it's me
My dear Marian, Marian
I cannot wait
Till he sets my heart free
Oh, when will I know him
Oh, when will I see her
When will I hear him say
Marian, my love