Ladies and gentlemen, welcome
to my underground lair.
I have gathered here before me
the world's deadliest assassins,
and yet each of you has
failed to kill Austin Powers.
That makes me angry, and
when Dr. Evil gets angry,
Mr. Bigglesworth gets upset.
And when Mr. Bigglesworth
gets upset...
People die!
Aah!
Ha ha ha!
Aaah!
Whoaaaa!
Aaaah!
Why must I be surrounded
by frickin' idiots?
Aah! Aah!
Aaaaaah! Aaaaaah!
Mustafa, Frau Farbissina,
I spared your lives because I
need you to help me rid the world
of britain's top secret agent,
the only man who can stop me now.
We must kill Austin Powers!
Yeah!
Come on, babies. Work
with me, people. All right.
Show me love.
Great, babies! Yeah!
Oh, behave.
Woman: It's Austin Powers!
[Women squealing]
It's Austin Powers! Aah!
[Beep beep]
Hello, Mrs. Kensington.
Hello, Austin.
Why don't you ever model
for me, Mrs. Kensington?
You know how Mr.
Kensington feels about that.
Oh, behave.
Heh heh heh, yeah!
Yeah, baby! Yeah, heh heh heh.
Ow!
[Musical beeping]
Hello, Austin.
I'm basil exposition
with British intelligence.
We have just received
word that Dr. Evil
is planning a trap for
you tonight
at the electric psychedelic
pussycat swinger's club
here in swinging London.
We'll be there.
[Women squealing]
Yeah, have a look, baby!
Whoo!
There you go. Come on, baby.
Yeah, yeah!
[The strawberry alarm clock
plays incense and peppermints]
Austin, it's a swinging shindig.
It's my happening, baby,
and it freaks me out!
Yeah, man!
♪ Little to win,♪
♪but nothing to lose ♪
♪ incense and peppermints,
meaningless finds ♪
♪ turn on, tune in,
turn your eyes around ♪
♪ look at yourself,
look at yourself ♪
♪ yeah, yeah
Can I get you a drink,
Mr. Powers?
Sure!
Austin, we've got
to look for Dr. Evil.
Wait.
I've got an idea.
Uhh!
Austin! Why on earth
did you hit that woman?
Right. Let me show you, baby.
That ain't no woman.
It's a man, man.
[Crowd gasps]
One of Dr. Evil's assassins.
Man: Look out! He's got a knife!
Good work, Mrs. Kensington.
All right, get up. Get up!
Right...Where's Dr. Evil, huh?
Where is he?
Uhh!
[Women scream]
There's the bastard.
Come on. Let's go.
Coming through.
Excuse me.
I've got you now, Dr. Evil.
Not this time.
Come, Mr. Bigglesworth!
See you in the future, Mr. Powers.
[Maniacal laughter]
My God!
He's freezing himself.
Basil: And so Dr. Evil escaped
and had himself
cryogenically frozen
to return at a time when
free love no longer reigned
and greed and
corruption ruled again.
[Telephone rings]
Yes?
Commander gilmour?
Speaking.
Commander, this is
ritter in sou-west com 3.
We have a potential bogey
with erratic vectoring
and an unorthodox entry angle.
What are you saying, son?
Well, it appears to be
in the shape of a big boy.
Good God... He's back.
Well, in many ways, the
big boy never left, sir.
He's always offered the same high
quality meals at competitive prices.
Shut up.
Shall I scramble tac
hq for an intercept?
What's its current position?
I'm presently tracking
it over Nevada.
Oh, my God! The big boy's gone.
Listen, son...
I want you to forget
what you saw here today.
Phillips... call
the president, sir.
Prepare the jet,
bring my overnight bag,
and, uh, Phillips, feed my fish?
Not too much.
I'm off to
London, eng-a-land.
Basil: Powers volunteered
to have himself frozen
in case Dr. Evil
should ever return.
Gilmour: Well, I hope
your boy's up to it.
We don't wanna have to
bail you guys out again
like after w.W.Ii.
Basil: This is our celebrity vault.
Please.
Russian officer: So, who
is this Austin Powers?
The ultimate gentleman spy:
Irresistible to women,
deadly to his enemies,
a legend in his own time.
Woman over speaker:
Attention. Stage one:
Laser cutting begins.
Laser cutting complete.
Stage 2: Warm liquid
goo phase beginning.
Warm liquid goo phase complete.
Stage 3: Reanimation beginning.
Reanimation complete.
[Coughing]
Stage 4: Cleansing beginning.
Cleansing complete.
Stage 5: Evacuation beginning.
[Urinates heavily]
[Urination continues]
[Urination stops]
Evacuation
comp--
[urination resumes]
[Urination stops]
Evacuation
com--
[trickling]
Com--
Evacuation
com--
[urination resumes]
[Mumbling]
Uh...Uh... Wh-where am I?
You're in the ministry of defence.
It's 1997.
You've been cryogenically frozen
for 30 years.
Who are these people?!
The shouting is a
temporary side effect of
the unfreezing process.
Yes. I'm having difficulty
controlling the volume of my voice!
This is commander gilmour,
U.S. strategic command,
and general borschevsky,
Russian intelligence.
Russian intelligence? Are you mad?
A lot's happened
since you were frozen.
The cold war's over.
Well, finally, those capitalist
pigs will pay for their crimes, eh?
Eh, comrades? Eh?
Austin... We won.
Oh, groovy. Smashing.
Yay, capitalism.
Hello.
Hello!
Mr. Powers... the
president's quite concerned.
We've got a madman on
the loose in Nevada.
Dr. Evil.
When do I begin?
Immediately.
You'll be working
with miss Kensington.
Mrs. Kensington!
Austin, Mrs. Kensington
has long since retired.
Miss Kensington is her daughter.
Ah, here she is.
Vanessa is one of our top agents.
My God, Vanessa's
got a fabulous body...
And I bet she shags like a minx.
How do I tell them that because
of the unfreezing process,
I have no inner monologue?
I...Hope I didn't say
that out loud just now.
Heh heh heh...
Mr. Powers, my job is to
acclimatize you to the nineties.
You know, a lot's
changed since 1967.
No doubt, love, but as long
as people are still having
promiscuous sex with many anonymous
partners without protection,
while at the same time experimenting
with mind-expanding drugs
in a consequence-free environment,
I'll be sound as a pound.
Danger Powers--
personal effects.
Actually, my name is Austin Powers.
It says here "name--
danger Powers."
No, no, no, no, no.
Danger's my middle name.
Ok. Austin
danger Powers--
one blue crushed velvet suit...
Hey, all right.
One frilly lace cravat...
There it is.
One silver medallion
with "male" symbol...
One pair of Italian boots...
Buon giorno, boys.
One vinyl record album:
Burt bacharach plays his hits...
Hey, Burt!
One Swedish-made...
Penis enlarger pump...
That's not mine.
One credit card receipt for
Swedish-made penis enlarger
signed by Austin Powers...
I'm telling you,
baby, that's not mine.
One warranty card for
Swedish-made penis enlarger pump
filled out by... Austin Powers...
I don't even know what this is.
This sort of thing
ain't my bag, baby.
One book: Swedish-made
penis enlarger pumps and me:
(This sort of thing
is my bag, baby)...
By...Austin Powers.
Uh...Just sign the form.
Ok, don't get heavy,
man, I'll sign it,
just to get things
moving, you know.
You're all right, baby.
Listen, Mr. Powers.
I look forward to working with you,
but do me a favor and
stop calling me "baby."
You can address me
as... Agent Kensington.
Oh, come on.
All right, then... Vanessa.
Was that so hard?
Now come along. We have
to leave immediately.
We preserved your private
jet just as you left it.
It's waiting at Heathrow airport.
My jumbo jet! Smashing, baby!
Oop...Sorry.
Mr. Powers?
Quickly.
Quickly. Come on, lad. Let's go.
Dr. Evil: Gentlemen, welcome
to my underground lair.
It's been 30 years, but I'm back.
Everything's gone perfectly to plan
except for one
small flaw--
due to a technical error
by my henchman Mustafa,
complications arose in
the unfreezing process.
But my design was perfect.
Look what you did
to Mr. Bigglesworth!
But, Dr. Evil, we were
unable to anticipate
feline complications to
the reanimation process--
silence!
Aah!
Aaaaaaaaah!
Let this be a reminder to you all
that this organization
will not tolerate failure.
[Mustafa moans in agony]
Gentlemen, let's
get down to business.
[Mustafa moans in agony]
We've got a lot of work to do.
Mustafa: Someone help me!
I-I'm...Still alive, only
I'm very... Badly burned.
Some of you I know,
some of you I'm meeting
for the first time.
Mustafa: Ah-ah! Hello
out there! Anyone!
Could someone call an ambulance?
I'm in quite... A lot of pain.
Ok, you've all been
gathered here to form--
ohhh! Excuse me.
Yes. He's down there.
No, not dead--
burned. Badly.
Yes.
Right.
Mustafa: If somebody
could open the retrieval
hatch down here,
I could get out.
See, I designed
this device myself--
[hatch opens] Oh! Hi. Good.
I'm glad you found me. Listen...
I'm very badly burned,
so if you
could just--
[gunshot]
You shot me!
Ok, moving
along--
you shot me right in the arm!
Why
did--
[gunshot]
[Retrieval hatch closes]
Right.
Let me go around the table
and introduce everyone.
Frau Farbissina: Founder of the
militant wing of the salvation army.
Random task: Korean ex-wrestler,
Evil handyman extraordinaire.
Random task, show them what you do.
[Neck cracking]
Patty o'brien:
Ex-Irish assassin.
His trademark-- a
superstitious man,
he leaves a tiny keepsake
from his good luck bracelet
on every victim he kills.
Scotland yard would
love to get their hands
on that piece of evidence.
[Irish accent] Yeah, they're
always after me lucky charms.
[Tittering]
[Chortling]
What? Why's everyone always
laugh when I say that?
They are after me lucky charms!
What?
[German accent] It's a
television commercial...
With this cartoon leprechaun,
and all of these childrens
are trying to chase him--
"hey, leprechaun man!
Won't you give your lucky charms?"
Oh, and there's always
these little, tiny
bits of marshmallows
just stuck right in the cereal
so that when the kids
eat them, they think,
"oh, this is candy.
I'm having fun!"
Finally, we come to
my number-two man.
His name:
Number Two.
For 30 years, number
Two has run virtucon,
the legitimate face
of my evil empire.
Dr. Evil, over the last 30 years,
virtucon has grown
by leaps and bounds.
About 15 years ago, we
changed from volatile chemicals
to the communications industry.
We own cable
companies in 38 states.
We own a steel mill in Cleveland,
shipping in Texas, oil
refineries in Seattle,
and a factory in Chicago
that makes miniature
models of factories.
Naturally, yes.
Gentlemen...
I have a plan.
[Meow]
It's called blackmail.
As you know, the
royal family of britain
are the wealthiest
landowners in the world.
Either the royal family pays us
an exorbitant amount of money,
or we make it seem
that prince Charles
has had an affair
outside of marriage,
and therefore...
Would have to divorce.
Ahem.
Prince Charles did have an affair,
he admitted it, and
they are now divorced.
Right. Ok, people,
you have to tell me
these things, all right?
I've been frozen for 30 years, ok?
Throw me a frickin' bone here.
I'm the boss. Need the info.
Ok, no problem.
Here's my second plan:
Back in the sixties,
I developed a
weather-changing machine,
which was, in essence, a sophisticated
heat beam which we called a "laser."
Using these "lasers,"
we punch a hole
in the protective
layer around the world,
which we call the "ozone" layer.
Slowly, but surely,
ultraviolet rays would pour in,
increasing the risk of skin cancer.
That is unless... the world
pays us... A hefty ransom.
Ahem.
That also... already has happened.
Shit.
Oh, hell, let's just
do what we always do--
hijack some nuclear weapons and
hold the world hostage. Good.
Gentlemen, it's
come to my attention
that a breakaway Russian
Republic-- kreplachistan--
is about to transfer
a nuclear warhead
to the united
nations in a few days.
Here's the plan:
We get the warhead, and we
hold the world ransom for...
$1 million!
Ahem.
Don't you think we should maybe ask
for more than a million dollars?
A million dollars isn't exactly
a lot of money these days.
Virtucon alone makes
over $9 billion a year.
Really? Mm-hmm.
That's a lot more.
Ok, then.
We hold the world ransom for...
$100...Billion!
Pretty groovy jumbo jet, eh?
When you see this jet a-rockin',
don't come a-knockin', baby! Yeah!
I'm going to need you to
sign these release forms.
Release forms?
Yes. You're not officially working
for ministry of defence,
and these forms indemnify
the ministry against any...
Mishaps that may occur
in the line of duty.
Mishaps? But isn't that what being
an international man
of mystery's all about?
Ok. "Name." Austin...
Danger Powers.
"Sex." Yes, please!
How does a hot chick like you
end up working in the
ministry of defence?
Oh. Well, I went to Oxford,
where I excelled
in several subjects,
but I ended up specializing
in foreign languages.
I really wanted to travel.
You know, sort of see the world?
That's fascinating, Vanessa.
Listen, why don't we
go in the back and shag?
What?
I've been frozen for 30 years.
I've gotta see if my bits
and pieces are still working.
Excuse me?
My wedding tackle.
I'm
sorry--
my meat and 2 veg,
my twig and berries.
Hello, lads, you still awake?
Mr. Powers, please.
I'd appreciate it
if you could concentrate
on our mission
and give your libido a rest.
Can I, uh...
Can I show you something?
♪ If you're feeling
sad and lonely ♪
♪ there's a service
I can render ♪
♪ tell the one who
loves you only ♪
♪ I can be so warm
and tender... ♪
I won't bite...Hard.
All right.
Let me ask you a
question, and be honest.
Oh!
Do I make you horny?
Randy?
Do I make you horny,
baby? Yeah, do I?
I hope this is part of
the unfreezing process.
Oh, turbulence! Oh, look at that!
Oh, turbulence! Oh, I've gone over!
Oh, I fell over again!
Oh! Mr. Powers!
I will never have
sex with you, ever!
If you were the last man on earth
and I was the last woman on earth
and the future of the human race
depended on our having
sex simply for procreation,
I still would not
have sex with you.
What's your point, Vanessa?
♪ Don't be afraid,
you can call me ♪
♪ maybe it's late,
but just call me ♪
♪ tell me and I'll be around ♪
Yeah!
Remember when we froze your semen?
You said if it didn't look
like you were coming back,
we should try to make you a son
so that a part of you
could live forever.
Oh, sure.
Well, after a couple of years,
we...Got a little impatient.
Dr. Evil, I want
you to meet your son.
My son?
Ja.
Scott!
[Grunge rock playing]
Hello, Scott.
Hi.
I'm your father...
Dr. Evil.
I haven't seen you my whole life,
and now you come back
and just expect a relationship?
I hate you.
What?
Could I have a hug?
No.
Give me a hug. No way.
Come here. I'm not
coming over there.
Let's go. Forget it.
Pronto. What are you doing?
I'm with it. I'm hip.
♪ Dukka-dukka, dukka-dukka,
dukka-dukka, dukka-dukka ♪
♪ dukka-dukka, dukka-dukka,
♪ haa!
Don't look at me like
I'm frickin' frankenstein.
Give your father a hug.
You're--hey,
don't touch me!
Hug...Hug...Hug...
Get away from me,
you lazy-eyed psycho!
Austin: Viva Las Vegas, baby! Yeah!
Whoa. Whoo! Whoo!
Welcome to Las Vegas, sir.
So...
Which side of the bed do you want?
You're sleeping on
the sofa, Mr. Powers.
In fact, I'd like to take
this opportunity to remind you
that the only reason
we're sharing a room
is to keep up the context
that we're a married
couple on vacation.
Right.
Should we shag now,
or shall we shag later?
How do you like to do it?
Do you like to wash up first,
you know, top and
tails, whore's bath?
Personally, before I'm on the job,
I like to give my undercarriage
a bit of a
how's-your-father.
I'm just joking, Vanessa.
I'm just trying to get a
rise out of you, that's all.
For shits and giggles.
Let's unpack.
Gor blimey...
Nude alert!
How did this get in here?
Somebody's playing a prank on me.
Honestly, it's not mine.
Hey, Americans, yeah!
Enjoy that wine.
Hey, there you are.
Hi. Do I know you?
No, but that's where
you are. You're there.
Hey, viva Las Vegas, baby.
Hey...
Ok, Austin...
Yes.
Austin, there's a
company in Las Vegas
called virtucon
which we think may
be linked to Dr. Evil.
Plenty of the virtucon executives
are gambling in this casino.
Smashing. Let's go.
Look. There's one over there.
Changing 1,000.
Hello.
Excuse me.
Do you mind if I join you?
Not at all.
Dealer: The game is
Blackjack, gentlemen.
$10,000 minimum bet.
King for you, sir, and a 3 for you.
17?
Hit me.
You have 17, sir.
I like to live dangerously.
4. 21.
5.
I'll stay.
I suggest you hit, sir.
I also like to live dangerously.
Dealer: As you wish, sir.
20 beats your 5.
I'm sorry, sir.
Well, I won't lie to you.
Cards are not my bag, baby.
Allow myself to introduce...
Myself.
My name is Richie Cunningham,
and this is my wife Oprah.
My name is Number Two.
This is my Italian
confidential secretary.
Her name is alotta...
Alotta Fagina.
Come again?
Ah, I'm sorry. I'm
just not getting it.
It sounded like you said
your name was a lot of, uh...
Never mind.
What exactly do you
do, Mr. Number Two?
That's my business.
Oh.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I have to go to the
little boys' room.
You keep your eye
on the Italian bird.
We'll rendezvous back
at the hotel suite.
You didn't happen to see...
Anything at all.
Ah. Sorry.
Ow!
Howdy.
[Coughing]
Whoo!
That is one crazy getup
you got there, fella.
Oh, thank you.
Are you in the show?
Uh, no. Actually, I'm English.
Whew. I'm sorry.
Right.
Hey, partner?
Have a good one.
Ok.
Ughhh...
Hey, partner, come on,
you gotta relax. Don't force it.
Gonna blow out your
o-ring, drop a log.
Ughhh...
[Whistling]
Who does Number Two work for?
That's right, buddy. You
show that turd who's boss.
Hey...Hey, just grab
ahold of something,
bite your lip, and
give it hell. Come on.
We're gonna get through this.
[Gurgling]
Hey, that sounds pretty nasty.
How about a courtesy
flush over there?
[Flushes toilet]
Jesus Christ, boy.
What did you eat?
Gentlemen,
the warhead is ours.
Patch me through to the united
nations security secret meeting room.
[Beep]
Gentlemen, my name is Dr. Evil.
In a little while you'll notice
that the kreplachistani warhead
has gone missing.
If you want it back,
you're going to have to pay me...
$1 million!
[Laughter]
Ahem.
Sorry.
$100 billion.
Oh! Oh!
Gentlemen, silence.
Now, Mr.
Evil--
Dr. Evil.
I didn't spend 6 years
in evil medical school
to be called mister,
thank you very much.
It is the policy of
the united nations
not to negotiate with terrorists.
Really?
So long.
[All talking]
Gentlemen, in exactly 5 days
we will be $100 billion richer.
Heh heh ha ha ha...
Ha ha ha ha ha!
Ha ha ha ha ha...
Ho ho ha ha ha ha hah!
Uh, ha ha ha ha...
Heh heh heh heh...
Uh, ha ha ha...
Ooh, Whoo...
Uh, heh heh...
Uh, heh...
Hello, mummy?
Oh, hello, Vanessa.
And how's Austin?
He's asleep.
You didn't.
No!
I made him sleep on the sofa.
Vanessa, I'm proud of you.
Why?
Because you've managed to resist
Austin Powers' charms.
Oh, well, God knows
he tried, mummy.
I actually had to end up
being rather firm with him.
What about his teeth?
It's really bizarre.
Darling, you have to understand,
in britain in the sixties,
you could be a sex symbol
and still have bad teeth.
It didn't matter.
Did you ever?
Me? No, of course not.
I was married to your father.
Did you ever want to?
Austin is very charming,
very debonair.
He's handsome, witty,
has a knowledge of fine wines.
Women want him,
and men want to be him.
He's every bit an
international man of mystery.
Yeah, well, you didn't
answer my question, mummy.
I know.
Let me just
say this--
Austin was the most loyal and...
Caring friend I ever had.
I will always love him.
Oh...Ohh...
Do you want to speak to him?
No. It's been too long.
Ok, well, I'm going
to have to go, mummy,
but I love you.
Ciao, darling.
A limo's just pulled up.
Let me see.
That's Dr. Evil's cat.
How can you tell?
I never forget a pussy...
Cat.
Oh, no. He's gone away.
My God, Vanessa,
you are so incredibly beautiful.
Oh...
That's it...Yes...
Yes...Yes...
Come on, darling,
I'm gonna take you out
for a night on the town.
[Piano plays]
Ladies and gentlemen,
Mr. Burt bacharach.
♪ What the world
♪ needs now
♪ is love
♪ sweet love
♪ no, not just for some
♪ but everyone
♪ what the world
♪ needs now
♪ is love
♪ sweet love
♪ no, not just for some ♪
♪ but for...
[Up tempo] ♪ everyone
oh, yeah.
Oh, go on, Austin, get on with it.
I'm gonna do it...
Do it a bit.
Oh, go on...Yes!
Oh...
Right hand green!
Oh, no, no... Aah!
You all right?
You all right? Oh, you know what?
Wait a tick. I forgot
something in the lobby.
Why don't I take the stairs?
Why take the stairs when
I could take the escalator?
Why take the escalator when
I've got a perfectly good canoe?
Ha ha ha!
I know
what--
I'll take the elevator.
Austin.
Yes?
Come have some champagne with me.
Ok.
Oh, I tripped. Oh...
You know, I haven't had
this much fun since college.
Well, I'm sorry.
Why?
I'm sorry that bug up
your ass had to die.
Always wanting to have fun, Austin.
That's you in a nutshell.
No. This is me in a nutshell.
Help! I'm in a nutshell!
How did I get into this nutshell?
Look at the size of this
bloody great big nutsh--
what sort of shell
has a nut like this?
This is crazy.
Yes. Look at you.
No.
You're smashed.
No, I'm not.
Yes, you are.
No, I'm not. I'm the sensible one.
I'm always the designated driver.
Oh, kiss me.
I can't, darling.
Why not?
'Cause you're drunk.
It's not right.
No, I'm not drunk.
I'm just beginning to see
what my mummy was talking
about all those years ago.
I can't.
Ohh...
All right, well,
tell me all about my
mummy in the sixties.
I'm dying to know
what she was like.
She was very groovy.
Your dad loved her very much.
If there was one
other cat in this world
that could have loved her
and treated her as
well as your dad,
well, it was me.
But unfortunately...
For yours truly...
That train has sailed.
Vanessa?
Vanessa, hello?
Come on, roll over.
Sleepytime.
[Musical beeping]
Ok, Austin needs his hand back.
[Telephone speed dials]
Computer: You've got mail!
Hello, Austin.
This is basil exposition
from British intelligence.
Now, I want you to find out
what part virtucon plays in
something called project vulcan.
I'll need you to go to alotta
fagina's penthouse immediately.
Ahh...
Hello, hello.
[Click click]
Yes, yes, ok, great.
Project vulcan.
Yeah, ok.
Cheeky, huh? Yeah.
Come on, baby, give it to me.
Yes, yes, yes,
no, no!
[Footsteps]
You seem surprised to see me,
miss fagina.
What do you want,
Mr...Cunningham, was it?
Your boss--
Number Two--
I understand that cat's involved
in big underground drills.
How did you know?
I didn't, baby.
You just told me.
We can talk about business later.
Let me slip into
something more comfortable.
Oh, behave.
♪ The look
♪ of love
♪ is in
♪ your eyes
♪ a look
good God.
♪ Your smile
♪ can't disguise
♪ the look
♪ of love
♪ it says so much more
♪ than words could ever say ♪
♪ and what my heart has heard ♪
♪ well, it takes
my breath away ♪
♪ I can hardly
wait to hold you ♪
♪ feel my arms around you ♪
Come in...
And I'll show you
everything you need to know.
♪ You've got that
look of love ♪
♪ that's in
♪ your face
♪ and what my heart has heard ♪
♪ well, it takes
my breath away ♪
♪ I can hardly
wait to hold you ♪
♪ feel my arms around you ♪
♪ you've got the look
♪ of love
♪ it's on your face
may I wash you?
Oh, groovy, baby.
Mm, yes...
That feels yummy. Ha ha. Mm...
In Japan, men come first
and women come second.
Or sometimes not at all.
Care for some sake?
Sake it to me, baby.
Yes.
Kinky.
Klinky.
Ooh...
Ohh...
How do you feel, Mr. Cunningham?
Mm, I feel extreme relaxation.
Oh...
How dare you break wind before me?
I'm sorry, baby. I didn't
know it was your turn.
Pardon me for being rude.
It was not me. It was my food.
It just popped up to say hello,
and now it's gone back down below.
That's beautiful.
Thank you.
Let's make love,
you silly, hairy, little man.
I say! Hello, vicar.
Ooh. That's the spot, all right.
That's the spot right there.
Look at that, now. Good God.
Austin Powers is getting too close.
Any suggestions?
Jawohl, herr doctor.
I have created the ultimate weapon
to defeat Austin Powers.
Bring in the fembots!
[These boots are made
for walkin' plays]
♪ You keep sayin'
♪ you've got
something for me... ♪
Go, fembots!
♪ ...but confess...
These are the latest word in
android replicant technology.
Lethal, efficient,
brutal.
No man can resist their charm.
Send in the guards!
♪ These boots are
made for walkin' ♪
♪ and that's just
what they'll do ♪
Frau: Kill these women.
♪ These boots are gonna
walk all over you ♪
♪ are ya ready, boots?
[Meow]
♪ Start walkin'
quite impressive.
Thank you, herr doctor.
I like to see girls
of that...Caliber.
By caliber, of course,
I mean both the size
of their gun barrels
and the high quality
of their character.
It's 2 meanings.
Caliber--it's
a homonym.
Forget it.
At ease, boys.
Austin, I want to
show you something.
We're going to
outfit you with this.
It looks like a watch,
but in fact it's a
geosynchronous positioning device.
Very shagadelic.
And then there's this.
Ok, let me guess.
The floss is garrote wire,
the toothpaste is
plastic explosives,
and the toothbrush is
the detonation device.
No, actually.
Well, since you've been frozen,
there have been fabulous advances
in the field of dentistry.
W-what do you mean?
Nothing.
Oh, look, here's basil.
Hello, exposition.
Austin.
Let me bring you up to speed.
Dr. Evil has hijacked
a nuclear warhead
from kreplachistan.
Only 2 things scare me,
and one is nuclear war.
What's the other?
Excuse me?
What's the other
thing that scares you?
Carnies.
What?
Circus folk.
Nomads, you know.
Smell like cabbage.
Small hands.
Oh...Indeed.
Perhaps these photographs are
the last piece of the puzzle.
Aha.
I've uncovered the
details of project vulcan.
Oh, good God. An
underground missile?
Austin, where did you find these?
Austin did some
reconnaissance work last night
at Alotta Fagina's penthouse.
Oh.
Our next move is to
infiltrate virtucon.
Any ideas?
Oh, yes.
Virtucon runs a tour of
its facility every hour.
I thought perhaps we could
disguise ourselves as tourists
and do some onsite reconnaissance.
Top drawer, Kensington.
Oh, uh, Austin, I'd like
you to meet somebody.
This is
my mother--
Mrs. exposition.
How do you do?
Vanessa: Austin!
My God, man, what have you done?
That's not your mother.
It's a man, baby!
Get off! Get off! Come on!
Why won't this wig come off?!
Uhh! Uhh!
Austin!
Yeah, hold on. Hold on one second.
No, no. Let go of my mother!
Oh...Oh, mother.
Mother, are you all right?
Austin, have you gone mad?
No.
You have a lot of explaining to do.
I'm sorry, basil. I
thought she was a man.
Damn it, man, you're
talking about my mother!
Well, you have to admit,
she is rather mannish.
Austin!
Well, no offense,
but if that is a woman,
it does look like she was
beaten with an ugly stick.
Really, Austin.
Ok, give in to the beauty of
your feelings and say the words.
Come on.
I love you, dad.
I love you, too, son.
Ok, group,
we have some newcomers
here today with us.
Say hello to Scott and
his father Mr. avil?
Evil, actually.
Dr. Evil.
All: Hello, Dr. Evil. Hello, Scott.
Hello, everybody.
So, Scott, why don't
we start with you?
What brings you here with us today?
Well, I just really met my dad
for the first time 5 days ago.
I was partially
frozen his whole life.
That is beautiful
that you can admit to that.
He comes back,
and now he wants me to take
over the family business.
But, Scott, who's going to
take over the world when I die?
Listen to the
words he used--
"who's going to take over
the world when I die?"
It feels like that to some
of us sometimes, doesn't it?
So what do you want to do, Scott?
I don't know.
I was thinking I like animals.
Maybe I'd be a vet.
An evil vet?
No. Maybe, like,
work in a petting zoo.
An evil petting zoo?
You always do that!
I just think, like, he hates me.
I really think he wants to kill me.
Now, Scott, we don't want
to kill each other in here.
We might say that we do sometimes,
but we really don't.
Actually, the boy's quite astute.
I really am trying to kill him,
but so far, unsuccessfully.
He's quite wily like his old man.
This is what I'm talking about.
Ok, well, we've
heard from you, Scott.
Now, uh, you tell us
something about yourself.
The details of my life
are quite inconsequential.
Oh, no, please, please.
Let's hear about your childhood.
Yeah. Come on.
Very well.
Where do I begin?
My father was a
relentlessly self-improving
boulangerie owner from Belgium
with low-grade narcolepsy
and a penchant for buggery.
My mother was a 15-year-old French
prostitute named Chloe with webbed feet.
My father would
womanize, he would drink.
He would make outrageous claims
like he invented the question mark.
Sometimes he would accuse
chestnuts of being lazy,
the sort of general malaise that only
the genius possess and the insane lament.
My childhood was typical.
Summers in rangoon, luge lessons.
In the spring, we'd
make meat helmets.
When I was insolent, I was placed in
a burlap bag and beaten with reeds.
Pretty standard, really.
At the age of 12, I
received my first scribe.
At the age of 14,
a zoroastrian named vilma
ritualistically shaved my testicles.
There really is nothing
like a shorn scrotum.
It's breathtaking.
I suggest you try it.
You know, we have to stop.
Vanessa: Austin, can
I have a word with you?
Of course you may, love.
Look, I know I'm being neurotic,
but I can't shake off this suspicious
feeling about that Italian secretary.
You know, miss fagina.
I don't want to sound paranoid,
but I've had some bad
relationships in the past,
and I have been
known to be jealous.
I'm sorry.
No. Don't be sorry, baby.
You're right to be suspicious.
I shagged her.
What?
I shagged her rotten, baby, yeah!
I don't believe you,
Austin. She was repellent.
Saucer of milk, table 2. Meowr.
But did you use protection?
Of course. I had my 9mm automatic.
You know I meant
did you use a condom?
Ha ha ha. Only sailors
use condoms, baby.
Not in the nineties, Austin.
Well, they should,
those filthy beggars.
They go from port to port.
Vanessa, don't have a thrombo.
Alotta meant nothing to me.
Well, it means something to me.
Austin, if you want us
to have a relationship,
you have to get it into your
head that times have changed.
You can't just go off
shagging anybody anymore.
And if you could, I wouldn't
because I'm not like that.
Vanessa...
You're everything to me.
You just don't get it, do you?
Good night, Austin.
Welcome to the nineties.
You're going to be very lonely.
Hey. Check this guy out.
Peace. Peace.
Yeah.
Jimi Hendrix...
Deceased...
Drugs.
Janis joplin.
Deceased, alcohol.
Mama cass.
Deceased, ham sandwich.
[Static]
[Squeaks]
[Pooshh]
Astronaut: Oh, gee, that's great.
Is the lighting halfway decent?
Announcer: Yes, indeed.
They got the flag up now.
You can see the stars and stripes.
Astronaut: Beautiful.
Just beautiful.
[Crowd chanting]
Vanessa: Good morning, Austin.
You know, I sometimes forget
you've missed out
on the last 30 years.
Fall of the Berlin wall,
the first female
British prime minister,
end of apartheid.
Yeah, and I can't
believe liberace was gay.
I mean, women loved him.
I didn't see that one coming, no.
Guide: The tour is about to begin,
so if you'll please
take your seats.
Welcome to virtucon,
company of the future.
Virtucon is a leading
manufacturer of many items
you can find right
in your very own home.
Do you think she's
prettier than me?
Who?
You know who.
Oh, the Italian bird.
No, baby. She's rancid.
I think you're shagadelic, baby.
You're switched
on. You're smashing.
We make steel, petroleum
products, and volatile chemicals.
But don't worry about
the Italian bird, ok?
She's the village bicycle.
Everyone's had a ride.
On your right, you'll notice a
door leading to a restricted area.
Only authorized
personnel are allowed...
Austin: I'll take him.
You take her.
All right.
Let's go.
It's Bolton. We've got a problem.
[Alarm buzzes]
P.A.: Intruders in the complex.
Intruders in the complex.
Watch out.
Guard: Halt. This way.
Judo chop!
They're coming!
Hang on. I'm going to floor it.
Watch out. Move!
Move! Move!
Careful, Austin.
Nooooo!
Watch out!
Aaaah!
Aaaaah!
Eew. Ohh.
Let's go. Come on, let's go.
Oh! Thank goodness
we made it, Austin.
All right. Stay very cool, baby.
Ok.
Mr. Powers, welcome
to my underground lair.
You're just in time.
Enjoy the show.
Gentlemen, I give you the vulcan...
The world's most powerful
subterranean drill.
Does that make you horny?
Not now, Austin.
So powerful it can
penetrate the earth's crust,
delivering a 50-kiloton
nuclear warhead
deep into the liquid
hot core of the planet.
Upon detonation, every
volcano on earth will erupt.
[People gasp]
[All talking]
It seems we have no choice
but to pay your ransom.
You have my instructions. Bye-bye.
Check it out, butt-head.
This chick has 3
boobs. Heh heh heh.
How many butts does she have?
Ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha!
Do you like your quasi-futuristic
clothes, Mr. Powers?
I designed them myself.
Oww!
Scott! Scott, my boy, how are you?
How was your day?
Well, my friend sweet Jay
took me to that video
arcade in town, right?
And they don't speak English there,
so Jay got into a fight, and
he's all, "hey, quit hassling me
'cause I don't speak
French" or whatever.
And then the guy says
something in Paris talk,
and I'm like, "just back off."
And they're all, "get out."
And we're like, "make me."
It was cool.
Fascinating.
What are your plans
for this evening?
I thought I'd stay in.
There's a good tittie
movie on skinimax.
And that's how you'd like
to live your life, is it?
Yeah.
Pretty much, right.
Scott: What?
[Slap]
Ow!
Scott, I want you to
meet daddy's Nemesis,
Austin Powers.
What, are you feeding him?
Why don't you just kill him?
No, Scott. I have
an even better idea.
I'm going to place him in
an easily escapable situation
involving an overly
elaborate and exotic death.
Scott: Why don't you
just shoot him now?
I mean, I'll go get a gun.
We'll shoot him together.
It'll be fun. Bang!
Dead. Done.
One more peep out of you
and you are grounded, mister,
and I am not joking.
All right. Let's begin.
Dr. Evil, do you really
expect them to pay?
No, Mr. Powers.
I expect them to die.
Even after they pay me the money,
I'm still going to melt every city
on the planet with liquid hot magma.
Release the sharks!
Mr. Powers, you'll
notice that all the sharks
have laser beams
attached to their heads.
I figure every creature
deserves a warm meal.
Ahem. Dr. Evil, it's
about the sharks.
When you were frozen, they were
put on the endangered species list.
We tried to get some,
but it would've taken months
to clear up the red tape.
You know, I have
one simple request,
and that is to have sharks
with frickin' laser beams
attached to their heads.
Now, evidently my cycloptic colleague
informs me that that can't be done.
Can you remind me what
I pay you people for?
Honestly, throw me a bone here.
What do we have?
Sea bass.
Right.
They are mutated sea bass.
Really? Are they ill-tempered?
Absolutely.
That's a start, you know.
All right, guard, begin the unnecessarily
slow-moving dipping mechanism.
Oh!
Close the tank!
A-aren't you even
going to watch them?
They could get away.
No, no, no. I'm going
to leave them alone
and not actually
witness them dying.
I'm just going to assume
it all went to plan--what?
I have a gun in my room.
You give me 5 seconds, I'll get it.
I'll come back down here, boom!
I'll blow their brains out.
Scott.
You just don't get it, do you?
You don't.
It's no hassle.
Shh.
Shh!
But--
all I'm
say-- shh!
Shh! They're
gonna get--
I--
shh!
Shh!
I'm--
would--
shh!
Knock knock. Who's there?
Shh!
Look--
let me tell you a little story
about a man
named--shh!
Shh! Even before you start,
that was a preemptive shh!
Just know that I have a whole
bag of shh! With your name on it.
Aah!
What's your plan?
First, I plan to soil myself.
Then I'm going to regroup
and come up with a new plan.
Any thoughts?
Wait a minute.
I always have this
with me, just in case.
Ok. I get it.
I have bad teeth.
No, Austin. The floss is to
swing ourselves onto the ledge.
Ohh!
All right. Hold on.
Austin: Got it. Ok. Toothpaste.
Hello.
Judo chop!
Aah!
Hang on!
Hoh!
Judo trip.
No!
Eww! Aw!
Eww!
[Belch]
Not a good time to lose one's head.
Indeed.
That's not the way
to get ahead in life.
No.
It's a shame he
wasn't more headstrong.
He'll never be the head
of a major corporation.
Ok. That'll do. Ok.
Oh, no! What are we gonna do?
Oh, look. There's an
emergency exit. Go get help.
I'm gonna stay here and
keep an eye on Dr. Evil.
Ok. I'll hurry back.
Listen, Vanessa.
Whatever happens,
I want you to know
that I feel really bad
about that Italian bird.
What I'm trying to say is...
That if you want me
to be a one-woman man,
well, that's just groovy, baby.
Behave.
Come, everyone.
Let us repair to the main chamber.
Project vulcan is about to begin.
Scott, don't you want to see
what daddy does for a living?
Blow me.
Excuse me?
Show me.
Ok.
Dr. Evil: Position the vulcan.
Dr. Evil: Bring in the warhead.
Ooh.
Hello, hello.
Hello, Mr. Powers.
Care to have a little fun?
No, actually, I, uh...
I have to save the world.
Oh. Oh.
Is it cold in here?
Arm the probe.
Yeah...
No! No. No, I've
got to get Dr. Evil.
I've got to get Dr. Evil.
No, no, no. Um, baseball,
uh, cold showers.
Baseball. Cold showers.
Give it up, Mr. Powers.
Margaret Thatcher
naked on a cold day.
Man: Right up positions.
Vanessa: Gentlemen.
Let's lock and load.
Man: Right, lads. Hup,
hup, hup, move, move, move!
Don't go.
Stay with us. Don't go.
Please don't go.
You can't resist us, Mr. Powers.
Au contraire, baby.
I think you can't resist me.
Woman: ♪ you're the one
♪ who makes me come runnin' ♪
♪ you're the sun
who makes me shine ♪
♪ when you're around,
I'm always laughing ♪
♪ I want to make you mine
♪ I close my eyes
♪ and see you before me
♪ I think I would die
♪ if you were to ignore me
♪ have a good see
♪ just how much I adore you ♪
♪ I'd get down on my knees ♪
♪ I'd do anything for you
♪ I don't want anybody else ♪
♪ when I think about
you, I touch myself ♪
♪ ah-ah-ah, I don't
want anybody else ♪
♪ oh, no, oh, no, oh, no
I want you.
I don't want anybody else.
When I think about you,
I touch myself.
Ooh.
♪ I
♪ I don't want anybody else ♪
♪ when I think about
you, I touch myself ♪
♪ ah-ah-ah, I don't
want anybody else ♪
♪ when I think about
you, I touch myself ♪
♪ I touch myself
Austin?
Vanessa!
Uh, it's not what it seems.
At ease, boys.
Likewise.
Vanessa, I can explain.
What happened was I broke
in trying to get to Dr. Evil.
Then all of a sudden,
the fembots came by,
and smoke started to come
out of their jumblies.
So I thought I'd
work my mojo, right?
To counter their mojo.
We got cross-mojonations, and
their heads started exploding.
You know, that thing, and I
ended up in my knickers here,
and then...
Ok, Austin, I believe you.
Now, get dressed.
Smashing, baby.
Onward, boys.
Launching the subterranean probe.
P.A.: Begin initial
surface penetration.
Subterranean nuclear detonation
in 3 minutes and counting.
Uhh. Aah!
Man: Watch out!
Man: ♪ there's a man who leads
right front!
♪ A life of danger
subterranean nuclear detonation
in 3 minutes and counting.
♪ To everyone he meets,
he stays a stranger ♪
♪ every move he makes
♪ another chance he takes
oh, I tripped!
Ow! Ow! Ow!
Open the frickin' door!
♪ Secret agent man,
secret agent man ♪
P.A.: Probe destruction
beginning in...
♪ They've given you a number
and taken away your name ♪
Aah!
P.A.: 6...
5...
4...
3...
2...
1...
Nooooo!
P.A.: Abort. Abort. Abort.
[Cheering]
Now to Dr. Evil.
Din-din.
♪ I want chicken,
I want liver ♪
♪ meow mix, meow
mix, please deliver ♪
I've got you now, Dr. Evil.
Well done, Mr. Powers.
We're not so different, you and I.
However, isn't it ironic
that the very things
that you stand for--
free love,
swinging parties--
are all now in the nineties
considered to be...
Evil?
No, man.
What we swingers
were rebelling against
is uptight squares like you
whose bag was money
and world domination.
We were innocent, man.
If we'd known the consequences
of our sexual liberation,
we would have done
things differently,
but the spirit would've
remained the same.
It's freedom, baby.
Yeah!
Face it.
Freedom failed.
No, man, freedom didn't fail.
Right now we've got
freedom and responsibility.
It's a very groovy time.
There's nothing more pathetic
than an aging hipster.
All right, baldy.
Shut your cakehole.
Come on. Let's go. On your bike.
Not so fast.
It seems the tables
have turned, Mr. Powers.
Go ahead, Austin.
Don't worry about me.
Hey, I can take my
sega, right, dad?
It seems the tables have
turned again, Dr. Evil.
Not really. Kill
the little bastard.
See what I care.
But, dad, we just had
a breakthrough in group.
I had the group
liquidated, you little shit.
They were insolent.
I hate you! I hate you!
I wish I was never
artificially created in a lab.
Scott, that hurts daddy
when you say that, honestly.
Ah, Number Two. Your
timing is impeccable.
Go ahead. Take Mr. Powers away.
No.
What?
Dr. Evil, I've spent
30 years of my life
turning this two-bit evil empire
into a world-class multinational.
I was going to have a
cover story in Forbes.
But, you, like an idiot,
wanted to take over the world.
And you don't realize
there is no world anymore.
It's only corporations.
Silence, Number Two!
No!
[Whining] I've had enough
of you pushing me around.
[Sobbing]
Mr. Powers...
I have a business proposition
you might find very interesting.
All right. I've had enough.
Whoa!
Aah!
Judo chop!
[Alarm buzzes]
P.A.: The complex
will self-destruct.
Let's split! Let's go!
This place is gonna blow!
[People shouting]
P.A.: The complex
will self-destruct.
Come on. Let's go.
P.A.: The complex
will self-destruct.
This way, Austin.
Come on, baby! It's gonna blow!
Let's go. Move it!
Alley-oop!
Aag. Ohh!
Ooooh...
[Alarm buzzes]
[Bells chime]
[Man laughs]
[Vanessa chuckles]
[Austin groans]
Yeah. Mmm.
[Chuckles]
I love you, Mr. Powers.
And I love you, Mrs. Powers.
[Musical beeping]
Oh, that'll be basil exposition.
Oh, ignore it, Austin.
Come back to bed.
Duty calls, baby.
[Beep]
Hello, Austin.
Oh, I--I hope I'm not
interrupting your honeymoon.
No, not at all, basil.
Did you get that fruit
basket I sent you?
Yes, we did, basil,
but you sent too much.
I'm gonna have to
send some to my mother.
Oh, don't forget these.
Oh, thanks.
There you go.
Did you get my other gift?
We did.
Yes, basil, nice rack.
But who in the world
gave us this drawing?
It's bizarre.
Well, as you know, Dr. Evil
has escaped in his rocket,
which has disappeared
from our tracking system.
Oh, dear, hold on. Coffee?
Oh, yes, please.
Ok. Thank you.
Oh, and Vanessa, by the way,
you have been made a full agent.
Oh, that's fantastic,
basil! Thanks.
Milk?
Oh, yes, please.
And, Austin, her majesty the queen
informs me that you are to be knighted.
Very shagadelic!
Well, the best of
luck to both of you!
Thanks, basil.
Good-bye.
You know, Vanessa,
I'll never forget the
first time I saw you.
You were so incredibly beautiful...
So incredibly sexy...
I knew I had to have you.
Right then and there.
Did you feel the same way?
Actually, I couldn't stop
staring at your teeth.
Oh.
[Knock on door]
Oh, I ordered some
champagne. Come in!
Vanessa: Oh, lovely, Austin.
Austin: Right over
there's fine. Thank you.
Let's go out on the terrace.
It's a beautiful night.
We can look at the stars.
Smashing idea, baby, yeah.
Look at you.
Yeah.
[Neck cracks]
[Gasps] Look out!
That really hurt!
I'm going to have a
lump there, you idiot.
Who throws a shoe? Honestly.
You fight like a woman.
Ha!
Ahhhh-ahhhh-ahhhh.
Grr!
Austin.
Honestly, it's not mine.
No, use it.
Uhh!
[Crash]
[Woman screams]
♪ 'Cause you will
never show... ♪
Look how beautiful
the night sky is.
Hey, isn't that the big dipper?
Yeah, and that looks
just like uranus.
Austin.
Well, you know.
Hey, I've never seen
that big star before.
Yeah. What is that?
Austin: Good God.
I'm gonna get you, Austin Powers.
It's frickin' freezing
in here, Mr. Bigglesworth.
[Trembling meow]
♪ Austin Powers
♪ he's the man for you
♪ Austin
♪ Powers
darling, you look fabulous.
Ok, baby.
All right.
There we go.
Look at that face.
Show me. Come on.
There. Bit of hair, bit of hair.
Smashing. Ok.
It's coming around
now. Coming around. Yes.
Yes. Great. Yes. Yes.
Yes. No! No!
No, it's not working!
Go change. There you go.
Can you change her? Is
that ok? Is that all right?
Very good.
And right here.
Right here. Looking right there.
I'm not even looking.
Oh, you're wicked!
You got your mojo working
overtime, darling. Yeah.
Look. I'm not even
shooting it. It's insane.
Smashing.
Come on. Can I get a smile?
Ok, come on.
Come on, you boys.
Get together. Come on.
Ok, good. Lovin' it.
Let's make a Vanessa sandwich.
The winged horn, the winged horn.
Come on, Austin.
Give it to me. Go. Go.
Oh, behave.
Ok, you're an animal!
An animal!
Yes.
Yes! That's it.
Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Just the top of the
hair. That's all I want.
Born and shoot.
Again. Try it one more time.
And, um, born and shoot.
That's it. Yeah.
Let's go. Come on. Come on.
Come on!
Ignore this. Ignore this.
Ignore me doing this.
♪ Watch out, someone's
gonna get me ♪
♪ I know it's never gonna... ♪
Fabulous, darling.
♪ That's just the way it
tends to be these days ♪
♪ I try, it never...
Go! Go! Go!
♪ What it gonna get me
♪ that's just the way it
tends to be these days ♪
Lord. Lord.
♪ These days
♪ these days yes, yes, yes, yes.
Show me the eye.
Yes. Yes.
Yes. No! No! No!
Never get up. Oh, spit!
We'll take you... [Camera breaks]
And we'll go out on the town
and swing, baby. Yeah.
♪ Missis
♪ will ya
♪ make me tea?
♪ Make love to me
♪ put on the telly
♪ to the BBC
♪ to the BBC,
yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ BBC 1
♪ BBC 2
♪ BBC 3
♪ BBC 4
♪ BBC 5
♪ BBC 6
♪ BBC 7
♪ BBC heaven
♪ missis
♪ will ya
♪ make me tea?
♪ Make love to me
♪ put on the telly
♪ to the BBC
♪ to the BBC,
yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ BBC 1
♪ BBC 2
♪ BBC 3
♪ BBC 4
♪ BBC 5
♪ BBC 6
♪ BBC 7
♪ BBC heaven
♪ missis
♪ will ya
♪ make me tea?
♪ Make love to me
♪ put on the telly
♪ to the BBC
♪ to the BBC,
yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ BBC 1
♪ BBC 2
♪ BBC 3
♪ BBC 4
♪ BBC 5
♪ BBC 6
♪ BBC 7
♪ BBC heaven
♪ BBC peace
♪ a thousand thundering
thrills awake me ♪
♪ facing insurmountable
odds greatly ♪
♪ the female of the species ♪
♪ is more deadlier
than the male ♪
♪ shock, shock,
horror, horror ♪
♪ shock, shock, horror
♪ I'll shout myself hoarse
♪ for your supernatural force ♪
♪ the female of the species ♪
♪ is more deadlier
than the male ♪
♪ oh, she deals
in witchcraft... ♪