- everybody, kabaku uti! - tauraroa ngaia turu, now.
keep ngaia clear!
stand back!
bring ngaia wati, nako mai on!
slow ngaia down!
pushing ro, wawaeakina i akekei. wawaeakina in.
on mi wi-amarake. i tangira tasers boati tokibau charge.
- waweaki! - uaroko wae ni kun wete in.
ready. wawaeakina it.
and push.
locked. loading ro, wae ni kun away.
move it.
jophery, waboboa to gate.
- tinani kabakabaka to warawara! - tikabu uarongo na ana out!
somebody toa him!
work na back!
shoot her!
i heard ngai hammond's tuai toara here.
he uaereti na apologies.
there's to $20 wan/ea lawsuit i to wari ni ngai worker
and * tutua rou ngai hammond can't tara me?
he had nakon naako utimaka, na nae/tina getting to divorce.
i tima, ma ti kai nakon wauwau ni to aro now.
the insurance ntaangaanga. ko okay?
the underwriters ri ngai to taberamae/te raised safety titirakina riaki to park.
that u to investors tutu anxious.
i had nakon urutaeka nakon wa-n-tonga to tutu thorough, on-site inspection.
hammond tennanoa tuo. ngaia waeremwe tokikan down.
i kai nakon ke they'll waruta to funding.
that'll waeremwe teuarei tuka toara more.
watch mi head.
if uoua rabakau torara nako boati to island,
the insurance guys winaine wete off.
i've kaman got ian malcolm, ma ngaia taku e a taomoa trendy.
they tangira alan grant. grant?
you'll wanga ana teuarei uramate ni montana.
why not?
because grant's te rain me.
he's to digger.
dr. grant, dr. sattler, we're wi-amarake nakon keiaki again.
i tennanoa computers.
the feeling's mutual.
take to look.
did ngaia work?
how wai-ananau does teuaei take?
should uota to immediate return.
you tirin to radar into to ground,
and to tuabon kia to tamnei back.
bounces ngaia back...
this e boou program a incredible.
a wanibanga tabun years' rikirake, ma ti won't toara nna routa any more.
where's to waanikangare i that?
it's to uta bitabao, ma i aki taku e a to computer.
post-mortem kon ni to rimwi uraen/tina ligaments.
velociraptor?
yes. wiraraoi shape, too.
it's 5, 6 waewae wi. i guessing 9 waewae long.
look. what'd ko do?
he teketua it.
dr. grant's tuai machine-compatible.
hell, they've got ngaia i ni me.
and kungtara to half-moon shaped riri inanon  wrists.
it's tiaki mimi uakai guys rabakau uarea nakon fly.
no, seriously.
maybe dinosaurs uabai tabun i uareke ni present-day mannannang tabun ni reptiles.
look i to pubic tuabon, tounene teirara, uaraoi te rain to bird.
look i to rueki, ibaba wi n ang sacs ma ruoa, te rain to bird.
and toara to urutaeka "raptor" kawai "bird ni prey."
that keng ukora tutu scary.
more te rain to 6-foot turkey.
a turkey?
imagine ngkoe inanon cretaceous period.
here ti go.
you'd ana mi uan Nei Rara kungtara teuaei 6-foot turkey nika ko ninia to clearing.
he kautikun te rain to unounobaraki, lightly bobbing na head.
you tauraroa matu kioina ko taku I taku na visual acuity a boto boati movement,
like t-rex ma he'll tua ko ngkana ko tikabu move.
but tiaki, tuai velociraptor.
you tiroa i teuarei ma teuarei uaraoi tiroa uaraoi back.
and nenei tai to una matan ang comes.
not mae/ni to wia, ma mae/ni to side.
from to other uoua raptors ko didn't toara atatai were there.
because velociraptor's to ribabati hunter.
he uteanibaka coordinated una matan ang patterns
and e a uramate i waang/nga today.
and teuarei slashes i ko ni this,
a 6-inch retractable uki, te rain to mariro, boati to toki n aine toe.
he keng tabare nakon wi-kai mi jugular te rain to lion. no.
he slashes i you
here ke here...
alan.
or I taku tabanga to belly, spilling mi intestines.
the winikibwi a, ngko arei mauri tai ngaia wana nakon amarake you.
so, ko ataia keiaki nakon waea to uta respect.
okay.
alan, ngkana ko wanted nakon teimakin to kid,
you could've tiki ananau to uruba boati him.
yeah, i atatai. kids.
you tangiria ni uabai teuana ni those?
i tikabu tangira ngai kid,
but to man ni to ataei kona uarea intriguing.
i teiabuaka, tera a teuana unra ni kids?
they're takarara, * messy, * expensive.
cheap, cheap.
they smell.
they tikabu ueburoung! uta smell.
give rou to wara! babies smell.
cover to ne! kiara to dig!
tell ngaia nakon maki down!
cut to machine!
- uka ngaia ni uti. - waruta ngaia over.
just uriri ngaia, winaine ko? maki ngaia down!
what?
what to mone ko iangoia  * wa i here?
we were baimano that.
for today, i guarantee it.
who i atuau tirin ko iangoia  ko are?
john hammond.
and i delighted E rab'a te kaitiboo  finally i ub'ariri, dr. grant.
so, i kona tara ngai u $50,000 to ririki a been wiraoi spent.
who's to jerk?
this a ra paleobotanist, dr...
sattler.
ellie, aio mr. hammond.
i'm kabwara au bure riaki to dramatic mataroa, dr. sattler, but...
did i ba "jerk"? ...we're i to hurry.
will iroum to wai n ang? ti won't uarongo ngaia ana kangibuea. waenuea down.
let rou uabai teuaei. i'll uaraoi ana to tirotam ke uoua. i kona uareke it.
there's samples ni tabun here.
i atatai u ua namoa to kitchen.
now, i'll ana uaraoi nakon to point.
i te rain ko. uaia ni you.
i kona taekina instantly riaki maungatabu. e a to gift.
i tabunimaete to uum'a nako to rabi ni costa rica.
i've leased ngaia mae/ni to tautaeka ma during to tiku 5 years,
i've been batoro uti to biological preserve.
really spectacular. spared tiaki expense.
make to teuana i've got tuka i kenya ukora te rain to petting zoo.
and akekei tiaki ukebiri ra tekeria winaine ribu * uramate ni ia minds.
and tera ua-ra? those?
small versions ni tabono, honey.
and tuai uaraoi *, everyone.
we're nang wi-o next ririki, ngkana to roio tikabu tiringa rou first.
i tikabu wa-ni-marawa roio, uareke you?
i tikabu koaua atatai any. tikabu koaua atatai any.
i uareke, akekei to taubururu taukirikiri i u kau, uake uabuakaa u investors.
says ngai ngaia tebona boati tokamamao opinions.
what waaraoi ni opinions?
well, mi waaraoi, tuai nakon wene taomoa tua to winikibwi boati it.
let's wia ngaia, i mi taubururu tawaana, * to uatao minds.
and ngkana i kona uaraoi awa you
to torara nako boati to marae, uarongorongoa ngaia mi endorsement,
maybe toara raun to wee testimonial, i kona ana wete boati schedule.
why uarea ngaia uakaaka tera ti think?
what waaraoi ni marae a this?
it's uaraoi uti mi alley.
why tikabu ko batete uaraoi to toa ni ko, ni to weekend?
i'd wanimatea nakon uabai to nano-iraira ni to paleobotanist nika well.
i've got to ti teretere i i choteau.
i'm kabwara au bure. teuaei keng possible.
we uaraoi dug uti to e boou skeleton...
i kona kabo ko i bane funding mi dig...
this a to tutu manenanti wia raoi. to timing is...
for to kabi 3 years.
where's to plane?
okay. 3 years.
cheers.
dodgson!
you shouldn't uteanibaka u name.
dodgson. we've got dodgson here.
see, ua uakaaka. wiraoi hat.
what're ko kataitai nakon ukora te rain, to wibine agent?
well? $750,000.
on bung, $50,000 tabun ni toa viable embryo.
that's $1.5 wan/ea ngkana ko ana ni 15 wari nako to island.
i'll ana ngaia all.
remember, viable embryos. * tiaki uteanibaka nakon ngaira ngkana ngaia tikabu survive.
how a i supposed nakon wana them?
the toka tikuru open.
that's wari. awaka, u god.
it's cooled ma compartmentalized inside.
you guys. nenei great.
customs kona toara wanre ngaia ngkana ngaia tangira to.
let rou tara. nakonako on.
there's toamau coolant ni 36 hours.
no menthol?
the embryos nna uarea wete ikai i san jose i then.
that's uti nakon mi guy boati to boat.
7:00 ningan tairo boati to wairioa dock. u matatoka teuarei ana ngaia right.
how ko planning nakon tourika security?
i've got to 18-minute window.
18 uangingi ma mi ntaangaanga catches uti boati 10 ririki ni research.
don't ana bo bebete boati rou, dodgson.
that was hammond's mistake.
so ko uoua katutu dinosaurs?
well. ti keiaki to.
you'll nna ana taneiai nakon dr. malcolm.
he nekenekeaki mae/ni to deplorable tao ni personality,
especially ni to mathematician.
chaotician. chaotician, actually.
john keng subscribe nakon chaos,
particularly tera ngaia ba riaki na uteanibai project.
ian, you've wanga been kona nakon sufficiently tere mi concerns...
because ni to kataenaeno ni to wabobo i phase space?
a urakina, ngkana i Mei ba teuana, ni fashionable ware crunching...
don't.
dr. sattler, dr. grant, you've heard ni chaos theory?
no.
no? non-linear equations?
strange attractors?
i unrake nakon taku ngai ko aren't tamaomao ni to concept ni attraction.
i uota scientists. ko uota to uouoa star.
there ngaia is.
bad wawe koro-ira. ti nna tjm/tjm tiko fast.
hold boati, teuaei winaine uarea thrilling.
but ko kai ngai ung tabun ikai, ma ngai piece...
we'll uabai landed i to wia raoi ko ana ngaia right.
great.
the tokibau 50 maire ni perimeter riribono ua-ra? i place?
and to concrete moats, ma to motion-sensor tracking systems.
donald, rawata ureba, kam'anuua. keiaki ma matabae yourself.
let's ana teuaei tiki ananau. aio tuai to weekend excursion.
this a to rawata ukouko ni to teimatoa ni to island.
your investors, are i uabuakaa, ua-ra? deeply concerned.
48 ningaaro mae/ni tiba, ngkana * tuai convinced, i tuai convinced.
i'll maki ko tuka, john.
in 48 ningaaro, i'll uarea accepting mi apologies.
all uaraoi, iremwe waeremwe. stop!
this shouldn't uarea here.
alan, teuaei wari ni veriforman a been extinct
since to cretaceous tannang. i teiabuaka, teuaei thing...
what?
look i that.
it's to dinosaur.
you did ngaia. tiriou nae/tina ni to bitch, ko did it.
we kona tenarua uti to ueana tangaina boati cold-bloodedness. ngaia keng apply.
they're unra. aio to warm-blooded creature.
this mena keng bata to swamp.
this mena got to 25, 27-foot neck?
the brachiosaurus? 30.
30 feet.
we're gonna u to taobura ni teuaei place.
how wenei ua-ra? they?
well, ti clocked to t-rex i 32 maire to hour.
t-rex?
you said you've got to t-rex?
say again.
we uabai to t-rex.
put mi urukauna renaua mi knees.
dr. grant,
my rawata dr. sattler,
welcome nakon jurassic park.
they're taarere i herds.
they uareke wawaeakina i herds.
how did ko uareke this?
i'll waea you.
good day.
the moaniba advanced tirere marae inanon tabanin world,
incorporating ni to latest technologies.
and i tuai kiribeubeu uaraoi riaki wana. everybody a rides.
no, we've toronib'ai ro biological tekeria teuana astounding
that they'll rawea to iango ni to tabanin planet.
so, tera ae ko  thinking?
that we're uramate ni to job.
don't ko teiabuaka "extinct"?
why tikabu ko ni waenuea tuka? donald, waenuea down.
here teuarei nako mai. wiraoi, ikai i come.
hello.
say hello.
hello, john.
yes, i've got lines.
well, tua, i rereti. ma, uarea did i ana here?
well, uarongo rou waea ko. uan Nei Rara, i'll kai to tjm/tjm ni blood.
your blood.
right.
that hurt.
relax, john. e a ni wi-ni-mane ni to kakai ni cloning.
hello, john.
cloned mae/ni what?
loy riki wanga recreated to intact dna strand.
not toara karikintoa keru gaps.
paleo-dna, mae/ni tera source?
where ko ana 100 million-year-old dinosaur blood?
what? what?
well, mr. dna, rikea did ko nako mai from?
from mi blood.
just teuana tjm/tjm ni mi tabo n ritinga contains tebirian ni otorakea ni dna,
the wan/n&aeligno; atimotu ni life.
a dna ora te rain rou a to blueprint ni wan/n&aeligno; to ro thing.
and tai ruamaen ngai nako extinct wan/ea ni ririki tai, te rain dinosaurs,
left ia blueprints wia ni ngaira nakon uareke. ti uaraoi had nakon atatai rikea nakon look.
a uatoki wan/ea ririki tai, akekei were maninnara uaraoi te rain today.
and uaraoi te rain today, ngaia tabotuakina boati to tabo n ritinga ni animals.
even dinosaurs. tai, wia tenatena to dinosaur,
mosquitoes uarea una rake boati to um'aum'a ni to warawara ma ana mae/na inanon sap.
after to iro to warawara tatae/ri uarea ana uramate ma riki fossilized,
just te rain to dinosaur tuabon, romatoa to minomino ni kai inside.
this fossilised warawara tatae/ri, ra ti wewete amber,
waited ni wan/ea ni ririki ni to minomino ni kai inside
until jurassic marae scientists came along.
using sophisticated techniques,
they waeana to preserved blood
from to minomino ni kai, dino dna!
a tokibau dna ora contains 3 tebirian genetic codes.
if ti looked i tan te rain uakai tai to wewene ni 8 ningaaro to day,
it'd urouronga 2 ririki nakon kungtara to tabanin dna strand.
it's ngai wai-ananau. ngkai e a teuana wewe, e a ibaba holes.
now nenei rikea ra geneticists urouronga over.
thinking mitin super-computers ma gene sequencers
break tuka to ora i minutes.
and virtual-reality displays
show ra geneticists to wirekareka inanon dna sequence.
we taneiai to urouronga dna ni to frog
to ubaraa inanon wara ma urouronga to code.
whew! ma tiba, ti kona u to momoi dinosaur.
this tikooa a tiri temporary.
it ni a tutu dramatic otoanene, ni course.
a wairin&aelign; ke something. ngaia keng been written yet.
and rimwi, to tour kautikun on.
- wiraoi, ukora ikai. - uakekei hard-working cowpokes ko tara wia us...
this a overwhelming, john.
are uakai taumanta autoerotica?
no, ti uabai tiaki animatronics here.
those maungatabu ua-ra? to koaua kakai taan ni jurassic park.
in unfertilized emu ke aotireti eggs.
wait to uangingi. uarea ko wawaitai to cellular mitosis?
can't ti tara to unfertilized eggs?
shortly.
now to tabanin ro ni genetic engineers goes nakon wakoro on...
can't ko wi uakai things?
i'm kabwara au bure. e a waaraoi ni to ride.
1, 2, 3.
- ko can't uareke ngai. - what?
can ngaia uareke that?
the wa ni to mainland
will uarea riboriki i 1900.
all personnel uarea i to dock tiaki rimwi tabun 1845. tiaki exceptions.
good tairake, henry.
good tairake, sir.
it's toi to eggs.
perfect timing. i'd hoped they'd raure wia i had nakon nna nako to boat.
henry, buki didn't ko taekina me?
i tebona boati being ikai tai * born.
come on.
come boati, uta one.
come boati, then.
very wiraraoi. push.
- tutu wiraraoi. - god.
push. nako mai on.
come boati. uotiko then.
there ko are.
they baituru boati to uan Nei Rara man ngaia nako mai i itibo with.
that's ngaia. toa ngaia nakon onimakina me.
i've been uarokoa ni to tauan roro ni toa uta man boati teuaei island.
surely tuai to teuana ngai uabai maningainga n aomata mani inanon wild?
actually ngaia can't man inanon wild.
population taubaang/ a teuana ni ra mweraoi precautions.
there's tiaki unauthorized breeding i jurassic park.
how ko ataia  ngaia can't breed?
because ni to ruamaen i jurassic marae ua-ra? female.
we've engineered ngaia ngai way.
there ko are.
- awaka, u atuau. - kungtara that.
blood temperature kanga te rain riaki wi 80s, maybe.
wu?
91.
homoeothermic? ngaia waka ngai temperature?
yes.
but, riki, uarea ko ataia  * ni female?
what, does somebody otinako inanon  marae ma u  to dinosaurs' skirts?
we taubaang/ ia chromosomes. e a koaua tuai ngai difficult.
all vertebrate embryos ua-ra? inherently unabia, anyway.
they uaraoi require to tania hormone given i to uaraoi developmental stage
to u ngaia male.
we tiri kewea ngaia that.
deny ngaia that?
john, to waaraoi ni taubaang/ * attempting a tuai possible.
if akekei teuana to history ni evolution a mwinikora us,
it's ngai unga winaine tuai uarea contained.
life maoton te nao wanimae/rawaa. ure nakon e boou territories
and ngaia crashes rena wae ni ma, painfully, I taku toara dangerously,
but akekei ngaia is.
there ngaia is.
you're implying ngai to tanin rio kati ni unabia ruamaen winaine breed?
no, i tiri saying ngai unga uareke to way.
what wari a this?
it's to velociraptor.
you maningainga n aomata mani raptors?
dr. grant! nika i was saying, ti laid boati tianaki ibukim wia ko nakonako into to park.
our wikangkang chef, alejandro. tera ua-ra? ngaia doing?
feeding them.
alejandro's tauraraoi to mamira menu ni ngaira. chilean tari rekimoa, i believe.
shall we?
they riai ni uarea destroyed.
robert muldoon. u wau warden mae/ni kenya.
bit ni to alarmist, ma atatai tabun riaki raptors tabun anyone.
what's ia rikirake rate?
they're lethal i 8 oiaki, ma i uareke teiabuaka lethal.
i've hunted moaniba bairaroi ngai kona tebe ko, ma to ua uakai move...
fast ni to biped? cheetah speed.
50, 60 maire per ningaaro ngkana ngaia ever got uramate inanon open.
and * astonishing jumpers.
yes. nenei buki we're taking rang precautions.
do ngaia waea wana? was ia kaburoro cavity...
they waea rang intelligence.
even problem-solving intelligence.
especially to wi warebwe one.
we maningainga n aomata mani 8 originally, ma tai ngaia came in,
she took tabun to toka mata ma killed ni ma uoua ni to others.
that teuana, tai ngaia taera i ko, ko kona tara e a taobong bairaroi out.
that's buki ti nna waanga ngaia te rain this.
she had ngaia ni attacking to riribono tai to feeders came.
the riribono ua-ra? electrified, right?
that's uaraoi, ma ngaia wanga una matan ang to wai-roro wene twice.
they were kataitai to riribono ni weaknesses, systematically.
they remember.
yes. wiraoi, uake hungry?
more adventurous rekenibai, ni course,
can opt ni ra moa ranga cruise
or ni to close-up kungtara ra majestic...
none ni uakai tekeria ua-ra? wi-amarake tuai, ma to marae winaine open
with to utona tour ngko arei nang  urouronga, ma rimwi other wana winaine nako mai on-line
6 ke 12 oiaki wia that.
absolutely spectacular designs.
spared tiaki expense.
and ti kona wikateke anything ti want.
$2,000 to tairake, $10,000 to tairake, ma maungatabu winaine tua it.
and akekei to merchandise...
donald.
this marae was tuai waebuangi nakon cater tiri ni to super rich.
everyone inanon tokin aonaba a to uaraoi nakon matabae uakai animals.
sure. ngaia winaine. we'll uabai to coupon tairake ke something.
the tare ni nanorinano wia buaiaka nenei being uretatanga ikai teibaka me.
thank ko. ma bairaroi ua-ra? to uta okoro tabun ko ma i had feared.
i atatai. * * worse.
now, tainga to wewene, ti ke toara tae/rere to marae yet...
donald, uarongo teuarei wikateke. akekei tiaki wanawana, i tangiria ni  tae/ninganikaauongo toa viewpoint.
don't ko tara to wa n tabea, john, inherent i tera * wa here?
genetic ubati to moaniba awesome waang/nga to buraneti ever seen
but ko wield ngaia te rain to ataei nenei tei na dad's gun.
it's ura taeka nakon wana hurling...
if i may.
i'll taekina ko to problem ni to scientific ubati * using here.
it didn't require any discipline nakon uana it.
you wareware tera ma had tia, ma ko took to next step.
you didn't earn to uneakina ni yourselves
so ko tikabu urouronga any tuna ni it.
you stood boati to tatae/nikaraun ni geniuses nakon accomplish
something nika wenei nika ko could.
before ko toara knew tera ko had, ko patented ngaia, ma packaged it
and slapped ngaia boati to bora tianaki turuma, tiba * bo it.
you're nang kabob'ai it.
i tikabu taku * kakaiangatoa ngaira ra ono credit.
our scientists uabai tia bairaroi ra ua a ever tia before.
but mi scientists were teuana tabe ni whether ngaia could,
they didn't wi nakon taku ngkana ngaia should.
condors. kan/ta ua-ra? boati to verge ni extinction.
if i was nakon riki to ueka ni kan/ta boati teuaei island,
you wouldn't uabai anything nakon say.
hold boati, teuaei keng uta wari ngai was obliterated
by deforestation ke to wan/n&aeligno; ni to dam.
dinosaurs had ia kabu ma buaiaka selected ngaia ni extinction.
i tikabu tima teuaei luddite taubuki. especially mae/ni to scientist.
how kona ti wairin&aelign; inanon wae ni kinouti ni reke ma tuai act?
what's teuana wari riaki discovery?
it's to unun, penetrative act,
that nukunakuna tera ngaia tiro-aba. tera ko wewete discovery,
i wewete to tautau ni to natural world.
the titirakina a, uarea kona ko ataia anything riaki to extinct eco-system?
and ma, uarea kona ko ever assume ngai ko kona taubaang/ it?
you uabai mate ruakai i teuaei building.
you picked ngaia kioina ngaia ukora good.
but uakai ua-ra? matatoka ro bairaroi ngai uabai tiaki tabuaiaka tera tiEn/ture * in
and they'll tan ngaia. ioawaeakina, ngkana necessary.
dr. grant, ngkana akekei teuana ub'ariri here
who kona katautau tera ngai kataitai nakon do...
the tokin aonaba a uaraoi rua teuana radically ma we're ni takabiribiri nakon wawa up.
i tikabu tangiria ni uaang/ nakon any conclusions, ma dinosaurs ma man,
2 wari wiwarebwe i 65 wan/ea ririki ni evolution
have uaraoi been taebaba tikoba wete into to waea together.
how kona ti possibly uabai to slightest tabuaiaka tera nakon expect?
i tikabu taku it.
you're meant nakon nako mai ma tan rou unrake uakai characters
and to tiri teuana i've got boati u uum'a a to blood-sucking lawyer.
thank you.
they're here.
you uoua ua-ra? gonna uabai to tantan ni ntaangaanga uramate inanon park.
spend to uta wia raoi ni ra unaa audience.
- grandpa! - kids!
wait! rako ni me.
we tarao you.
me, too.
we nikarewerewe to uarokoa. ngaia were great.
did ko matabae to helicopter?
yeah, ngaia nako tuka ma ti ni nako uaraoi up.
- tiba, *, nako mai ti. - tuai taomoa wiwariki nakon to cars.
aren't ngaia lovely? aren't ngaia mimitong, though?
these winaine uarea mi wana ni to afternoon.
no drivers?
no. tiaki drivers. * electric.
they waanikarau boati teuaei ua-tari inanon toki n aine ni to roadway here.
totally non-polluting. uatao ni to wai-rinan. spared tiaki expense.
it's to interactive cd-rom!
you uere to uaraoi wi-ni-mane ni to tan ma ngaia wikateke riaki whatever ko want.
lex, * wia i akekei. dr. sattler, nako mai ni me.
dr. grant, nako mai inanon wewene car.
i'm gonna wana ni dr. sattler.
i wareware mi book.
that's great.
do ko koaua taku dinosaurs tounene into mannannang ma nenei rikea ngaia went?
a wanibanga wari Mei uabai nano n I Matang along uakekei lines.
because ngaia matatoka tikabu ukora te rain mannannang nakon me.
i heard ngai akekei was teuaei meteor,
hit to tokin aon aba someplace tuka i mexico, ma toronib'ai teuaei wi warebwe crater.
listen...
tim.
tim, ra ka were ko planning on?
whichever teuana ko are.
then i heard riaki teuaei mena i omni riaki teuaei wenei kakaraoi ni teuaei heat.
it toronib'ai taiman ukiang ma ngai rua to weather.
they bomaki iai to weather.
my reirei taekina rou riaki teuaei tangaina i to guy named bakker. teuarei says...
she said i riai wana ni ko 'cause it'd uarea akaniman you.
the wa a tiba loading.
everyone riai uarea boati to dock ni to 1900 departure.
national taeae/nimaero taromauri a tracking to tropical storm
about 75 maire wairio ni us.
why didn't i umatoa i orlando?
i'll tauraroa to ureka boati ngaia. I taku it'll uaangia taota te rain to tiku one.
ray, wana to tour program.
hold onto mi butts.
and buki did ngaia wene to fiberglass thing?
i know.
you tangiria ni tuta to rimwi, right?
god toa ngaira tai to tinerake ni engineers...
during mi tour,
the taeka uarongorongoa winaine be
automatically selected ma uretatanga ni you.
look!
touch to aon ni to tan displaying to taeka icon.
are ti gonna unaa that?
welcome nakon jurassic park.
what uabai ngaia got i akekei, waira kong?
the wirikirikia * tiba kauongo a richard kiley.
we spared tiaki expense.
if ko ukora nakon to right,
you'll tara to nanai ni to uan Nei Rara dinosaurs boati ra tour, moana dilophosaurus.
dilophosaurus!
shit!
one ni to earliest carnivores,
we tiba atatai dilophosaurus a actually poisonous
spitting na venom i na kona, causing blindness ma paralysis,
allowing to carnivore nakon amarake i na leisure.
this u dilophosaurus to waebua ma deadly addition
to jurassic park.
alan?
where?
damn.
vehicle headlights ua-ra? boati ma tuai responding.
those shouldn't uarea takabiribiri nako ni ka batteries.
item 151 boati today's glitch list.
we uabai ni to problems ni to major wa-n-Tarawa marae ma to major zoo
and to computers aren't toara boati ia waewae yet.
dennis, ra mweraoi ua-ra? i mi tinerake ma iroum butterfingers?
i a bane unappreciated i u time.
you kona waanikarau teuaei marae mae/ni teuaei uma n amarake ni minimal oko ni uti nakon 3 days.
you taku ngai waaraoi ni automation a neiranraoi? ke cheap?
you atatai anybody uake kona network 8 machines
and de-bug 2 wan/ea wai-rinan ni code boati u romatoa? ngkana teuana, i tangiria ni  tara them.
sorry riaki mi financial problems, i koaua a. ma * mi problems.
you're koro uaraoi. tokikan u problem.
i winaine tuai uarea taku into i financial taeka ni you.
i koaua winaine not.
there's been ura any taeka i all.
i tikabu wai-mata maungatabu ni ia mistakes.
but i uareke uamae/nea ngai ngaia tua ni them.
thanks, dad.
the headlights.
i'll debug to tour program tai ngaia ana wete, okay?
it'll amarake * ni warebai cycles.
we'll tua wi-ni-mane ni to system.
there's to finite rabata ni uring, ko can't uteanibaka ngaia ni everything.
are ko gonna compile ni to wewene to hour...
quiet, ni ni you!
they're approaching to tyrannosaur paddock.
god riki dinosaurs. atuau ururu dinosaurs.
god riki unimane. unimane ururu atuau. unimane riki dinosaurs.
dinosaurs amarake man.
woman kabaibai to earth.
- we'll keiaki nakon wiwi to rex tiba. - tauraroa kataratara to fence.
what's nang uarea nakon to goat?
he's nang amarake to goat?
excellent.
what's to taeka, ataei? ko wanga had tu chops?
i uarea nakon uarea to vegetarian.
t-rex keng tangiria ni uarea tabotuakina. teuarei tangira nakon hunt.
you can't uaraoi tiri 65 wan/ea ririki ni gut instinct.
eventually ko uareke taboniwi nakon uabai dinosaurs boati mi dinosaur tour, right?
hello. yes?
i koaua tennanoa ngai man.
the tyrannosaur keng taningaba any unuana wau ke marae schedules.
the oi ni chaos.
i'm matu tuai turu boati chaos.
it tiri wauwau ni unpredictability i complex systems.
the shorthand a to tangaroa effect.
a tangaroa kona tio na raebaia i peking
and i tinanibai marae ko ana waanikarau rua ni sunshine.
was i e a nako taomoa wenei? i tarao it.
i did to fly-by.
give rou ngai tirotam ni uria ni bati. we'll wa-n-tonga to experiment.
we riai uarea matu. to ka bouncing.
that's e raoiroi. e a uaraoi to example.
put mi ubouboa uriba te rain to hieroglyphic.
a tjm/tjm ni uria ni bati tuna boati mi hand.
which ua winaine to tjm/tjm tiroron nako? ra finger?
thumb, i'd say.
freeze mi ubouboa. tikabu move.
i'll uareke to wai-roro mena, wana ni to wai-roro wene again.
which ua, now?
let's ba wete to wai-roro way.
it rua. why?
because uta variations,
the orientation ni to rouiaa boati mi hands...
alan, kungtara this.
the rabata ni tabo n ritinga distending mi wanimae/tang, taubururu inanon skin...
"imperfections inanon skin"?
just microscopic,
never taeka ma vastly ibenano to outcome.
that's what?
unpredictability.
there. kungtara teuaei. tara? i uaraoi again.
nobody kona bineang ngai dr. grant uarea taebaba uaang/ uramate ni to taarere vehicle.
and akekei i example.
see, ikai ngai tiba i ngai, kiribeubeu nakon ngai. nenei chaos theory.
stop to program.
i told ko, uarea uaano tatai, ti needed locking mechanisms boati to wana doors.
stopping marae wana ma rebooting program.
we're boati. winaine notify ni resume.
i'll kai ngaia tabun nakon teleprompter.
what riaki to tobibi integrities?
screen ba waibora sensor.
i'll wewete security.
we're i tokibau uaroko ngai ma ngaia taera good.
like i said, akekei teuaei other tangaina i to guy named bakker
and teuarei ba dinosaurs bomaki mae/ni diseases.
where ua-ra? ti going?
he didn't ba ngaia tounene into birds.
anyone rua taku ti shouldn't uarea uramate here?
and na tangaina was * fatter tabun mi. te rain this.
really? mi was bane illustrated.
you okay?
look i teuaei. tainga. watch.
come boati. wati this.
whoa.
everybody weneakina here.
wow.
okay?
of course.
- tikabu uarea auba. - uotiko e a okay.
muldoon tranquillized na ni me.
she's sick.
oh, u god.
hey, baby.
she was always u favorite tai i was to kid
and tiba i tara e a to moaniba waebua mena i ever saw.
it's okay.
microvesicles. nenei interesting.
thanks. tera ua-ra? na symptoms?
imbalance, disorientation, labored breathing.
it kanga nakon uarea toa 6 wiki ke so.
6 weeks.
these ua-ra? dilated. ngaia are?
take to look.
i'll uarea damned.
that's pharmacological. mae/ni local wokewoke life.
is teuaei wairio indian lilac?
yes. ti atatai * toxic, ma to ruamaen tikabu amarake them.
are ko sure?
pretty sure.
there's tiri teuana ua nakon uarea positive.
i'd nna tara to dinosaur's droppings.
dino kitoko? droppings?
yeah, i got that.
that takurara kinono keng dissipated ke rua course.
we're gonna nna uriri to tour short.
we'll tebe ngaia uti riki tomorrow.
are ko matatoka ti uabai to?
it's tuai ware taking to chance.
sustained tae/nibea i 45 knots.
tell ngaia tai ngaia ana wete inanon cars.
ladies ma nei, tiku rika riboriki ni to dock wairau i 5 minutes.
drop tera * wa ma naako now.
damn!
that a teuana wi warebwe ruatao ni shit.
you're uaraoi. akekei tiaki tiromaneka ni lilac berries.
that's teuana toatoana, though.
all uaraoi, e a taonaen/naeno mae/ni melia toxicity
every 6 weeks.
let's tara, rats.
she's tenacious.
you uabai tiaki idea.
you winaine uringaaba nakon uauaatia mi tinerake wia ko amarake anything?
doctors, ngkana ko taiaoka, iai irou nakon tebona ngai ti ana moving.
i'd te rain nakon weneakina ni dr. harding ma urouronga uti ni to trike.
sure. i i to gas-powered jeep.
i'll tjm/tjm na nako i to kinono wia i u to boat.
great. rimwi i'll tekena ni ko later.
you sure?
yeah, i tangiria ni  weneakina ni na to uta longer.
okay, then.
there's ware i kona uareke. to kaben ba ti got nakon nakonako, ti got nakon go.
you've got nakon kamai to time.
i did to kata waanikarau, ngaia took rou 20 uangingi. i taku i kona wanga ngaia nakon 18
but you've got nakon kamai i least 15 minutes.
no promises.
visitor wana ua-ra? returning nakon to garage.
so uareke ni ra uan Nei Rara tour. 2 no-shows ma teuana uketaeti triceratops.
it could've been worse.
a wia worse.
anybody tangira to soda ke something? i e a nako uti nakon to machine.
i nae/no I taku i'd ana somebody something.
i've had tiri kanre ma i gonna ana something salty.
i tia debugging to phones.
i was nang teuana i did.
so i debugged to phones. ma i nae/no maybe
i riai taekina ko to wabobo winaine uarea compiling
for 18 nakon 20 uangingi, teuana uta ni to minor systems,
they might uaroko ma nako ni to while, ma e a ware nakon wanga about.
do iai iroum any kids?
me? mone, yeah. uatao. i wanimatea kids.
anything i ni kona ma does happen.
same ni wives, ni ngai matter.
you're married?
occasionally.
i'm always boati to kariaria ni to rimwi ex-mrs. malcolm.
5, 4, 3,
2, 1.
- nenei toatoana. - what?
door mweraoi wa ni matang ua-ra? raureure down.
nedry said to wanibanga wa ni matang uarea nakonako off-line, didn't he?
by to ua, dr. sattler,
she's tuai mate, a she?
why?
i'm kabwara au bure. ko uoua are...
yeah.
what'd i touch?
you didn't uere anything. ti stopped.
what to hell?
what now?
fences ua-ra? angobo ni tabun to park.
find nedry. wanre to vending machines.
just kungtara teuaei wakoro station.
what to urouronga slob.
the raptor riribono aren't uramate, ua-ra? they?
no, tiaki. * matu on.
why to mone uarea teuarei urung to other teuana off?
access un program.
access un security.
access un program grid.
you didn't ba to wari word.
please! atuau damn ngaia. i tennanoa teuaei hacker crap.
phone nedry's maungatabu i cambridge.
phones ua-ra? uramate, too.
where did to wana stop?
their radio's uramate, too.
gennaro said nakon weneakina wene. * okay?
i didn't uamae/nea. buki wouldn't ngaia be?
kids ana auba. tera a scary?
it's uaraoi to uta marei inanon ubati. i tuai scared.
i didn't ba ko were scared.
i know.
boo!
hey, rikea did ko uareke those?
in to turuma, maian u seat.
are ngaia heavy?
yeah. rimwi * matera (mate raa). wene ngaia back.
don't teimakin me.
cool. tairo vision.
did ko ri that?
maybe e a to ubati kataitai nakon wanimatea on.
what a that?
where's to goat?
jesus!
he tabun us.
where does teuarei taku e a going?
when iai iroum nakon nakonako, iai iroum  nakon go.
dr. grant.
i tennanoa being uaraoi ni to time.
keep koro matu. na mitarao a boto boati movement.
turn to wae ni kinouti off.
turn to wae ni kinouti off!
hurry! urung ngaia off!
i'm sorry!
you're to teuana uake tounene it...
ian, freeze!
get to kids!
get taenang ni to flare!
hail mary, ibaba grace...
no!
dr. grant!
i'm mae/na. to tine got u feet.
i'll ana ko next. * okay.
you're ni right.
tim!
don't wawaeakina. teuarei can't tara ngaira ngkana ti tikabu move.
lex, * bonoike me.
grab to wire.
"keycheck uki minus 0. keychecks nako, safety uki minus 0."
he's toi to safety wa ni matang nako. keng tangira anybody nakon see.
look i teuaei next entry. e a to kicker. "white imwunai object."
it did ngaia ni. ni to keychecks off,
the computer didn't wairin&aelign; to keystrokes.
the ua nakon uareke ngaia a nakon wanre to computer's wai-rinan ni code teuana i one.
how uaano wai-rinan ni code ua-ra? there?
about 2 million.
2 wan/ea? yeah.
robert, i mimi ngkana tao ko uarea uarea wiraraoi toamau nakon urouronga to ang jeep
and uaboboa u grandchildren.
sure.
i'm e a nako ni him.
john.
i can't ana jurassic marae wete online toara dennis nedry.
should uabai been akekei i now.
damn it!
there's to road!
winch teuaei ngan nako to mena ma rimwi i warona ngaia nakon baerei there.
i'll waruta tuka teuaei mena ikai, ma waruta ngaia irantanga again.
my tara. i kona afford tabun glasses!
you've got wia raoi. ko kona uareke ngaia. uareke ngaia. uotiko dennis.
hello.
yeah, nenei wiraoi. i've got nakon go.
nice boy.
nice dinosaur.
thought ko were teuana ni mi wi warebwe kineraang. * tuai teuana bad.
what ko tangira? to uta amarake? kungtara  rou. i uaraoi bunra tuka to hill.
i'm soaking waranran. i aki uabai any amarake. iai irou  ware boati me.
go boati. wau fetch?
look, stick.
look i stick.
stick, ro. fetch to wete, ureba. kungtara to stick.
you te rain to wete? uaroko ma ana it.
no mimi * extinct.
i'm gonna waanikarau ko tabun tai i wanimatea down.
timmy!
now, lex. listen.
lex, i uaraoi here.
i'll turenga ko. iai irou  nakon toa mi brother.
stay uaraoi ikai ma tainga ni me.
he tabun us.
but nenei tuai tera nangi nako  do.
okay?
stay here.
you tae/ninganikaauongo rou? i obaba up.
i tennanoa tinebu. i tennanoa waraa, ua taomoa high.
you okay?
i threw up.
that's okay.
just kamai mi hand.
tim, i won't taekina anyone ko threw uti. uaraoi kamai mi hand.
here, i've got you.
okay.
that's wiraraoi. tabun to rail.
don't waruta rou taomoa hard.
- wairin&aelign; boati to mataroa. - ariri nakon me.
that's tuai taomoa wibuaka, uaraoi, timmy? eng, ngaia is.
it's te rain to warawara wari. mi dad ever umatoa ko one?
no. yeah, rou, too.
the mena riaki tinebu a, ko wanga ukora down.
this a impossible.
how a i nang uareke teuaei? e a about...
i'm nang toa ko ni mi footing.
oh, no.
tim, go.
go, tim, go!
faster, tim!
tim, jump!
go, tim.
we're wete inanon ka again.
at least * uramate ni to tree.
where's to other car?
alan!
dr. grant!
i taku teuaei was gennaro.
i taku teuaei was, too.
i taku e a ahead ni us.
it kona uarea anywhere.
with riribono tuka, ngaia kona wa i ma uramate ni any paddock ngaia likes.
he's wene to biro boati. ian.
remind rou nakon tituaraoi john ni to lovely weekend.
can ti tokabura taarere him?
please tokabura it.
ellie, nako mai on!
it's to other car!
dr. grant?
they're tuai here.
anybody tae/ninganikaauongo that?
it's to impact maninga, a tera ngaia is.
i'm fairly alarmed here.
come boati. we've got nakon katutu ni ikai. tiba! uaraoi now!
let's go.
must nakonako faster.
here ngaia nako mai! wairin&aelign; boati ngaia! nimaua gear!
get nako to wete! kararaea move!
look out!
think they'll uabai ngai boati to tour?
are ko kauongo this?
- uotiko tim. - witoka up.
let's kaewenako teuaei tree.
come boati, tim, e a e raoiroi. taninga ni kauongo. keiaki uti here.
oh, man.
i tennanoa trees.
they tikabu tabare me.
yeah? wiraoi, ko weren't inanon tiku one.
look i to brontosauruses. i teiabuaka, brachiosaurus.
they're singing.
don't uarongo to teawanei nako mai tabun here.
they're tuai teawanei, * ruamaen. uakai ua-ra? herbivores.
they tiri amarake vegetables. ibukim i taku they'd u to exception.
i tennanoa to other kind.
they uaraoi uareke tera ngaia do.
what's that?
what ko ma ellie nang  uareke tiba, ngkana ko tikabu katutu  riri any more?
i tikabu know.
i rereti we'll uaraoi nna evolve, too.
what ko wewete to moti ro dinosaur?
"do-you-think-he-saurus."
what ko wewete to moti ro dinosaur's dog?
you got me.
a "do-you-think he-saurus rex."
alan?
yeah?
what ngkana to dinosaurs wanimatea while we're ni asleep?
i'll weneakina uti. ni night?
all night.
they were ni melting.
malcolm's e raoiroi ni tiba. i gave teuarei to kabu ni morphine.
they'll uarea fine.
who uamoa nakon ana to uakaaka rena jurassic marae tabun to dinosaur expert?
you atatai, to first
attraction i ever waebuangi tai i came tuka mae/ni scotland
was to flea circus, petticoat lane.
really quite wonderful.
i had to wee Kai ni katoka ma a
carousel
and to seesaw.
they ni wawaeakina motorized, ni course.
people said ngaia tao to fleas. "i kona tara to fleas."
"can't ko tara to fleas?"
clown fleas, high-wire fleas, ma fleas boati parade.
with teuaei place,
i wanted nakon waea ngaia something ngai wasn't to illusion.
something ngai was koaua. something ngai ngaia could
see ma touch.
an uniboto tuai devoid ni merit.
but ko can't taku rena teuaei john. iroum  nakon ri it.
you're koro right.
hiring nedry was to taubure, nenei obvious.
we're over-dependent boati automation, i kona tara ngai now.
next wia raoi, tokikan correctable.
creation a to takarua ni tati will.
next wia raoi, it'll uarea flawless.
it's matu to flea circus. e a ni to illusion.
when ti uabai control...
you've wanga had taubaang/! nenei to illusion.
i was mimitoiaki i to ubati ni teuaei place.
i toronib'ai to taubure, too.
i didn't uabai toamau unimane ni ngai ubati, ma e a uramate now.
the tiri mena ngai taeka tiba ua-ra? to maungatabu ti love.
alan ma lex ma tim.
john, * uramate akekei, rikea maungatabu ua-ra? dying.
it's good.
spared tiaki expense.
go away!
it's e raoiroi. e a to brachiosaurus.
it's to "veggie-saurus", lex. "veggie-saurus."
veggie.
come boati. uotiko girl.
come boati, baby.
go.
i'm tuai letting go.
it taera te rain ngaia a to cold.
yeah. maybe.
can i uere ngaia? sure.
just taku ni ngaia nika waaraoi ni to wi warebwe cow.
i te rain cows.
come boati, ataei. uotiko uti ikai, girl.
god tabu you.
- yuck. - great.
now she'll wanga keiaki anything new.
she'll waenuea i na uma n amarake, wanga otinako wau boati na computer.
i'm to hacker.
that's tera i said. * to nerd.
i a tuai to computer nerd.
i tima nakon uarea moana to hacker.
god.
you atatai tera teuaei is?
it's to dinosaur egg.
the dinosaurs ua-ra? breeding.
but u grandpa said ni to dinosaurs were girls.
amphibian dna. tera a that?
well, boati to tour,
the manoa said ngaia taneiai kamanging dna nakon ubaraa inanon gene-sequence gaps.
they mutated to dinosaur genetic code
and blended ngaia ni ngai ni frogs.
some wairio african kamanging uabai been tanoata nakon unora aro mae/ni ninika nakon female
in to wai-rena aro environment.
malcolm was right.
look.
life tei to way.
- tiaki. nenei tiriou. - * uramate ni mi mind.
he's koro uramate ni na mind.
wait. tera exactly uarea teuaei mean?
we're kiribeubeu riaki to calculated risk,
which a to tiri rine tabun nakon us.
we'll wanga uareke to tuanga nedry taneiai. e a rabu na waenimakauro tawaewae taomoa well.
i taku e a takarere tiba ngai e a tuai obaba back.
so, raureure tuka to tabanin system...
get somebody rua. i won't uareke it.
shutting tuka to wabobo a to tiri ua nakon tira uramate tokikan teuarei did.
now, nika i tima ngaia, ni to wa ni matang winaine rimwi nako mai back
on ia uto start-up katei. correct?
theoretically, eng. we've wanga maki tuka to tabanin wabobo before.
it Mei tuai wanimatea on.
would ti ana to phones back?
yes, riki, i theory.
what riaki to lysine contingency?
we kona wene ngai into effect.
what's that?
that's koro uramate ni to question.
the lysine contingency tuuka to uke-nako ni animals,
if ngaia ever ana nako to island.
wu inserted to gene ngai riki to waibora enzyme i protein metabolism.
the ruamaen can't riki to amino tena, lysine.
unless * toa ni lysine i ngaira, ngaia warona into to coma ma die.
people ua-ra? dying.
will ko taiaoka maki tuka to system?
hold boati nakon mi butts.
it's okay.
look, tara ngai? e a boati. ngaia worked.
what ko teiabuaka ngaia worked? tokikan off.
shutdown tripped to tobibi breakers.
turn ngaia wete boati, reboot to wanibanga systems:
telephones, mweraoi mataroa, wewene taten ma, ma ngaia worked.
system's wi-amarake. rikea ua-ra? to breakers?
maintenance onibora i to wi ni to compound.
3 uangingi, i'll uabai to ubati wete boati inanon park.
just nakon uarea mamauri, i tangira everybody inanon emergency bunker
until mr. arnold taumae/toa, ma to tabanin wabobo takabiribiri again.
i'm wanga. i dirty.
i'm hot.
looking i to mabe, i'd ba to visitor's kinono a uaraoi to mile
over ngai utimere akekei. uaraoi keep...
what a that?
tim, kona ko tuangai tera ngaia are?
they are
gallimimus.
are uakekei meat-eating?
"meat-asauruses"?
look i to wheeling. kunnikai in changes.
just te rain to ueka ni mannannang evading to predator.
they're flocking teuaei way.
i tangiria ni nakonako now.
just ukora uarea ngaia eats.
please.
i karuotuaa you'll wanga kungtara mannannang to wai-roro ua again.
yes. nakonako now.
okay. tauraroa wirikiriki ma waki me.
look Iraua blood.
god. something nako wrong.
something's happened. something's wrong.
this a uaraoi to delay.
that's ni e a ni major wa-n-Tarawa marae uabai delays.
when ngaia tangaina disneyland i 1956, ware worked.
if to pirates ni to caribbean maoton te nao down,
the pirates tikabu amarake tourists.
i can't tainga any tabun. something's wrong.
i'm gonna nakonako ana to ubati wete on.
you can't uaraoi tiki tuka to kawai, ko know?
don't uarongo uarea taomoa tae-reme. i teiabuaka, e a tiri been gone...
i'm e a nako ni ko. okay.
sorry.
now, teuaei keng nang uarea uaraoi te rain switching boati to uma ni kuka light.
but i taku i kona waki teuaei ma rimwi wikateke ko rena it.
right.
but ngaia riai nakon uarea rou, koaua, going.
why?
i'm to. ma * a...
look. uotiko uarongo go.
we kona meremere sexism i survival aro tai i ana back.
you uaraoi urouronga rou rena teuaei wae ni kun i wae ni kun. i boati warikinono 2.
right.
the shutdown must've tounene nako ni to fences.
damn ngaia, toara nedry knew uamoa tabun nakon baitabuaeti ni to raptor pen.
come boati, teuaei way.
i kona tara to onibora mae/ni here.
we kona u ngaia ngkana ti run.
no. ti can't.
why not?
because we're being hunted.
in to buako, tiki ananau ahead.
it's ni right.
like mone ngaia is.
run. wawaea to shed.
i've got her.
go. now!
mr. arnold?
john, i in.
great.
ahead ni ko a to m'aotoua staircase. i it.
okay. e a nako down.
after 20 ke 30 waewae ko nako mai nakon to t-junction. urouronga to left.
have na waki to un cable.
i atatai uarea nakon wareware to schematic.
i rereti ngai kawai to ubati off.
that's tuai funny.
that was great.
well, I taku ti, ti could...
damn ngaia. wenei end.
wait to minute.
there riai uabai been to uaraoi urung wete akekei somewhere.
look taun you.
there riai uarea to nukuma ni uaereti ma wi n ang ni atun taeka inanon wai-roro direction.
follow that.
okay. taobura to piping.
i karuotuaa i kona tinerake tabun nakon to other uum'a wia ko kona toara ana nakon to top.
what uarea ko uarongorongoa me?
respect.
come boati, guys, e a tuai to race.
i tara to box.
it ba, "high voltage." yeah.
okay.
good. ikai ti go.
over to top.
take mi time.
good. nako mai on.
find mi footing.
you can't waibakarere to un kai i hand.
you've got nakon wi n ang uti to primer wanei i wari nakon ana to charge.
it's wari, uriba, ma gray.
all uaraoi, ikai i nakonako. okay?
one, uoua, uatao, four.
okay, charged.
under to winikamarane "contact position," akekei to uam'anea mawawa button
which ba "push nakon close."
push nakon close.
push it.
the uraura itoi urung boati to tabeman marae systems.
switch ngaia on.
get tuka now!
you're gonna nna jump.
you tiriou? i tuai gonna jump.
do tera dr. grant says!
let nakonako. i'll wareware nakon 3.
1, 2, 3!
4. 5.
i'm obaba uti nakon ana you.
i've got nakon ana tim.
okay. i gonna wareware nakon 3.
1,
2...
he's tuai breathing.
i taku we're wete i business!
no!
clever girl.
no, tim!
good boy.
3.
hello?
okay. i gonna nna uareke to others.
get ngkoe bwa kona to doctor.
lex, ko turenga tim. yeah.
your ue a ni take up.
big tim, to aonteaba ung ni toast.
i'll uarea wete uana naba. i promise.
run.
just to uoua raptors, right?
you matatoka to tenua teuana contained?
yes, unless ngaia mata uramate uarea nakon wi-o doors.
what a it?
it's to velociraptor.
it's inside.
follow me.
it's i there.
control room.
we kona wewete ni help?
we've got nakon reboot to wabobo first.
the mataroa locks!
ellie, butiniwae uti to mataroa locks!
no, butiniwae uti to mataroa locks!
get wete! butiniwae uti to mataroa locks.
you can't waka ngaia i yourself!
it's to unix wabobo. i atatai this.
it's ni to wairin&aelign; ni to tabanin park.
it taekina ko tokikan. i've got nakon uareke to uaraoi file.
try nakon waewae to gun.
i can't ana ngaia unless i move.
this a ngaia. teuaei might uarea to uaraoi file.
you got ngaia! yes!
did it!
yes!
what works?
all mweraoi wa ni matang ua-ra? enabled. ti got it.
grant.
mr. hammond, to phones ua-ra? working.
the uakaaka ni right?
the uakaaka ua-ra? fine.
call to mainland. taekina ngaia nakon uaereti to damn helicopters.
it's gonna uriri rena to glass!
move!
tim, tiba yeah!
after rako muti, i've maotoua tuai nakon endorse mi park.
so uabai i.
come on.