teuaei taun i ukraine was tai unata nakon tua 50,000 maungatabu.
it had tokikan to community uarea need for to toronibai life.
[indistinct chatter]
ma boati to 26th ni april, 1986, ngaia taebaba became uninhabitable.
the iai nuclear ubati station of chernobyl exploded.
[helicopter hovering]
and i kakarakoa tabun 48 hours, the taun was evacuated.
no teuana a lived ikai since.
to rebwe was to ua ni wibuaka planning ma aonteaba taubure. buretata.
ngaia triggered to environmental buanibai ngai had to impact tabanga europe.
many maungatabu regarded ngaia nika to moaniba costly in to history ni mankind.
ma chernobyl was to wai-rena event.
to koaua tragedy ni ra wia raoi a matu unfolding tabanga to globe,
takomkom noticeable mae/ni tairake nakon tairake.
i kiribeubeu riaki to taonaba ni ra buraneti tiriwenei wene,
na biodiversity.
the ro tokin aonaba a to unique and spectacular marvel.
billions ni tabeman, ma millions of waaraoi ni ruakai ma animals...
[birds chirping]
...dazzling i ia tei ma richness.
working uaiakina nakon benefit from to taururu ni to sun
and to tano ni to earth.
leading mweraoi ngai interlock i ikoa to way that ngaia ribata toa other.
we ongea kati boati teuaei finely tuned life-support machine.
and ngaia relies boati na biodiversity to waanikarau smoothly.
yet to ua ti aonteaba mweraoi boati tokin aon aba now is sending biodiversity into to decline.
[leaves rustling]
teuaei taomoa a rianibai nika to ua ni wibuaka planning ma aonteaba taubure
ma ngaia taomoa winaine urukauna nakon tera ti aio
a wene i ra ti cannot live.
to natural tokin aonaba a banikinauere.
to omatata a ni namoa. e a happened i u lifetime.
i've tae/rere ngaia ni u tabunimaete wai-mata.
teuaei manoa a u no taeka ma u mitarao ni to rimwi,
to wi-mari ni uarea ti came nakon u teuaei ra greatest taubure,
ma uarea, ngkana ti takarua tiba, ti kona tuai wene ngaia uaraoi.
ngai david attenborough, ma ngai  93.
i've had to moaniba bakanako unga.
e a tiri tiba ngai i katautau uarea bakanako.
[speaking indistinctly]
[attenborough] i've been tauraba enough to spend u life
exploring to tiriwenei wene ni ra planet.
i've traveled nakon toa wi-ni-mane ni to globe.
i've atataibai to ro world firsthand i ni na tei ma wonder.
in koaua, i couldn't imagine living u unga i any other way.
i've always had to wanimatea nakon explore, to uabai adventures,
to wareb'ai riaki to tiriwenei beyond.
[exclaiming i surprise]
and i matu learning.
boo!
as uareke tiba nika i did tai i was to boy.
[birds chirping]
it was to tutu okoro tokin aonaba wete then.
we had tutu uta understanding of uarea to ro tokin aonaba actually worked.
it was moana natural history
because nenei essentially what ngaia was ni about...
history.
it was to wari wene nakon nako mai nakon nika to boy,
kioina aio um, ironstone taobong, ma ngaia was disused.
ni teuaei was koro turu, ngaia was.
tiri uaraoi mate being to taobong quarry.
when i was to boy, i spent ni u tania time
searching rena rocks in wene te rain this...
for buried treasure.
fossils.
e a to man moana to tetoroa.
ma i unga to taimaeke oi lived inanon baonimoto ikai
ma tabangaka na kao nakon wawa na kona.
ma ngaia lived riaki 180 wan/ea ririki tai.
teuaei taubururu teuana a to scientific tirin ni tiltonicerus,
kioina to uan Nei Rara teuana ever was tei uramai teuaei quarry
ikai i tilton, inanon toki n aine ni england.
tabun wia raoi, i began nakon wareb'ai something riaki to tokin aon aba evolutionary history.
i ma wari, e a to wi-mari ni waeremwe, waweaki unora.
over tebirian ni years, nature a crafted mimi forms,
each tabun complex ma accomplished than to last.
it's to achingly intricate labor.
and then, every uatoki wan/ea ririki ke so,
after ni uakekei painstaking processes,
something catastrophic happens, a una extinction.
wari nimaatenten ni wari ribu ma ua-ra? taebaba replaced i to wanibanga.
all ngai evolution undone.
you kona tara ngaia. to wai-rinan inanon uouoa layers.
a toutia ngai uamania to profound, rapid, global change.
below to line are to uanao ni lifeforms.
above, tutu few.
to una mate nako a happened nimaung tatai i unga four-billion-year history.
the tiku wia raoi ngaia happened
was to event ngai brought to end of to wi ni to dinosaurs.
a wenei impact triggered a catastrophic change
in to tokin aon aba conditions.
75% ni ni wari were wiped out.
life had tiaki rine ma nakon rebuild.
for 65 wan/ea ririki, e a been i work reconstructing to ro world...
until ti nako mai nakon to tokin aonaba ti know... our time.
scientists wewete ngaia to holocene.
the holocene a been one ni to moaniba toronibai periods
in ra buraneti wari history.
[birds chirping]
for 10,000 ririki, to average temperature has tuai wavered uti ke down
by tabun tabun teuana rikuri celsius.
and to tokatake ma thriving living tokin aonaba namoa us
has been unora nakon teuaei stability.
phytoplankton i to ruruon surface and abakaei buakonikai straddling to north
have helped nakon tie to atmosphere by locking ti carbon.
huge nanai boati to plains
have reke to grasslands rich and mari i fertilizing to soils.
mangroves ma tab'anin reefs along w&aelign;/inga ni maire ni coast
have harbored nurseries ni wirikoi species
that, tai mature, then inneti into wi-o waters.
a rua-matoa tiringa ni moa namoa to equator has ngao wokewoke boati plant
to rawea nika uareke ni to tai energy as possible,
adding aoi ma oxygen to to global wi n ang currents.
and to abaki ni to polar ice has been critical,
reflecting sunlight back nako na white surface,
cooling to tabanin earth.
the biodiversity ni to holocene helped nakon uota stability,
and to tabanin ro tokin aonaba settled into to tiko, kakaonimaki rhythm...
the seasons.
[thunder rumbling]
[lowing]
on to tropical plains,
the tung ma taenibong tannang uarea switch every ririki te rain clockwork.
in asia, to tae/nibea uarea create the monsoon boati cue.
[thunder rumbling]
in to northern mone, to temperatures would waetebe i wairin&aelign;, triggering spring,
and weneakina wi uabong ngaia dipped i october and brought riaki autumn.
[birds chirping ma chattering]
to holocene was ra garden ni eden.
na katoang ni tannang was teuana kakaonimaki
ngai ngaia gave ra tabunimaete wari to takarere opportunity.
[mooing]
we invented farming.
we mariro n ang uarea nakon exploit to seasons to uamari amarake crops.
the history of all aonteaba tiwiriteetian followed.
each tamaroro able to utuaki ma progress
only kioina to ro world could uarea relied upon
to taenang ngaira to aro ti needed.
the rakaa ni wakiraoi was okoro anything to uarea tei inanon fossil record.
ra wana rua to ua i ra ti nano n I Matang.
inanon tarao,
ruamaen had nakon utuaki uta physical manikonana nakon unora ia mweraoi.
ma ni ngaira, to tabuaiaka kona uareke ngai.
ma to tabuaiaka kona uarea tae mae/ni teuana tamaroro nakon to next.
we were transforming what to wari kona achieve.
to wanibanga millennia wia teuaei began, i grew uti i exactly to uaraoi wia.
the wana ni u career i u 20s
coincided ni to advent of global wi n ang travel.
so, i had to privilege ni being amongst to first
to bane mwinikora to bounty ni life that had nako mai about
as to ua of the holocene's tiko climate.
wherever i nako, akekei was wilderness.
sparkling coastal seas.
vast forests.
immense grasslands.
you kona ub'ae/non ni hours over to untouched wilderness.
and akekei i was, actually being asked to tiro-aba uakai places
and record to wonders of to natural tokin aonaba ni maungatabu wete home.
ma nakon teirake ni, ngaia was quite neiranraoi.
maungatabu had wanga tae/rere pangolins wia boati television.
they'd wanga tae/rere aori wia.
ngaia had wanga tae/rere to kinono ni e boou guinea wia.
it was to taberanikai wia raoi ni u life.
to taberanikai wia raoi ni ra mweraoi.
the wewene tokin aonaba uouan te kai was over, technology was kakaraoi ra mweraoi easier.
the rakaa ni change was getting faster ma faster.
[indistinct chatter]
[attenborough] it felt ngai nothing would win te bike ra progress.
the rimwi was nang uarea exciting.
it was nang uota everything we had ever dreamed of.
teuaei was wia any ni ngaira were ata ngai akekei were problems.
my uan Nei Rara waeribono nakon wairioa africa was i 1960.
back rimwi, ngaia seemed inconceivable that ti, to wai-rena species,
might teuana tairake uabai to ubati nakon threaten the tutu riki ni to wilderness.
to maasai urutaeka "serengeti" kawai "endless plains."
nakon uakekei uake mweraoi ikai, e a to taine description.
ko kona uarea i teuana tantan boati to serengeti,
ma to wene a bane wa-ni-marawa ni ruamaen,
ma rimwi, to next tingaro.
[bellowing]
...one wan/ea wildebeest.
a renaba ni to wan/ea zebra.
[snorting]
half to wan/ea gazelle.
a wanibanga warebong wia that...
and * tarao. tabun to horizon.
you kona uarea forgiven ni thinking that uakai aoraoi ua-ra? endless
tai ngaia kona uka uti ikoa to nanai.
it took to buroburo scientist,
bernhard grzimek, to tere ngai teuaei wasn't true.
he ma na nae/tina taneiai to plane to waki to nanai tabun to horizon.
[grunting]
they charted them as ngaia takitaki tabanga rivers,
through woodlands, and tabun national borders.
they discovered ngai to serengeti herds
required to wari area of rung grassland nakon function.
that toara ikoa to abakaei space, the nanai uarea diminish
and to tabanin ecosystem would nako mai taururu down.
to winikibwi ni rou was simple: to tiriwenei a tawaewae mae/ni unlimited.
e a finite. ngaia kai protecting.
ma to wanibanga ririki rimwi, ngai tabuaiaka became takarere nakon everyone.
[nasa technician] five, four, three, uoua teuana, zero.
[attenborough] i was i to television studio tai to apollo mission launched.
it was to uan Nei Rara time
that any aonteaba had takitaki away far toamau mae/ni to earth
to tara to tabanin planet.
and aio tera ngaia saw...
what ti ni saw.
our buraneti, ikoa ma isolated.
one ni to bakanako bairaroi riaki it was ngai to world
kona actually wati ngaia nika ngaia happened.
ngaia was bakanako ngai ko kona tara tera to unimane uramate i uki kona tara
nika teuarei tao ngaia i to wai-roro wia raoi.
ma i uringaaba tutu wiraoi ngai uan Nei Rara kabu.
ko tao to uunikaai maaboro,
to uunikaai mron/ron inanon blackness, ma ko korobuki ngai ngai was to tokin aon aba.
ma i teuarei kabu, akekei was to tabanin ni bota ni ware rua
except to ub'ariri ngai was inanon spacecraft taking ngai tamnei.
ma ngai ni rua to mindset ni to population,
to aonteaba population ni to tokin aonaba.
our unata was tuai limitless.
there was to win te bike nakon ra existence.
ngaia was to rediscovery ni to fundamental koaua.
ti ua-ra? ultimately tourake i ma reliant ao
to finite natural tokin aonaba riaki ngaira.
this koaua defined to unga ti led in ra pre-history,
the wia raoi wia farming ma civilization.
even nika uta ni us were batoro waekirere boati to moon,
others were matu kairiri ikoa to life in to moaniba tabara wi-ni-mane ni to planet.
in 1971, i mananga nakon find an uncontacted tongabiti i e boou guinea.
these maungatabu were hunter-gatherers, as ni humankind had been wia farming.
[speaking tribal language]
[attenborough] they lived i wano numbers and didn't urouronga taomoa much.
[attenborough] they ate iwaka rarely.
the resources ngaia used naturally renewed themselves.
working ni ia traditional technology, they were ro sustainably,
a lifestyle ngai kona continue effectively forever.
[speaking imae/tang language]
[attenborough] it was to stark contrast to to tokin aonaba i knew.
a tokin aonaba ngai demanded tabun toa day.
i spent to latter wewene ni to 1970s traveling to tokin aonaba,
kakaraoi to uatao i had wai-ananau dreamed ni moana life boati earth,
the wi-mari ni to evolution ni life and na diversity.
it was kabu i 39 countries.
we filmed 650 species,
and ti traveled one ma to wewene wan/ea miles.
that's to tei ni commitment ko need
if ko tangiria ni toara begin making to tamnei ni to ro world.
ma ngaia was noticeable
ngai uta ni uakai ruamaen were wau harder nakon uareke.
when i filmed ni to maunga gorillas,
there were tiri 300 left in to tabara moa i tinanibai africa.
momoi gorillas were i to premium,
ma poachers uarea tiringa to taten tabono nakon ana teuana.
i got nika wiwariki nika i did tiri because the gorillas were taneiai nakon people.
the tiri ua nakon tauraroa ngaia alive was ni rangers nakon uarea ni ngaia toa day.
to tiki ni mate nako ngai i'd tae/rere nika to ureba. inanon babati,
i tiba became ata was rianibai uaraoi akekei namoa rou
nakon ruamaen ni ra i was tamaomao.
our closest relatives.
and ti were responsible.
it uki to timoi reality.
tai to wari became ra unaa,
akekei was tiba nowhere boati tokin aon aba ngai ngaia kona raba.
whales were being slaughtered i fleets of industrial whaling wari inanon 1970s.
the largest tokitoki, to blues,
numbered tiri to wanibanga w&aelign;/inga i then.
they were virtually impossible nakon find.
we tei humpbacks nako hawaii only i listening uramate ni ia calls.
to wia tai, ti toronib'ai teuaei recording
ni to underwater microphone ikai inanon pacific uramai hawaii.
uaraoi taeka teuaei.
[whales singing]
[whales tana singing]
recordings te rain uakai revealed that to kurara ni to humpbacks
are wai-ananau ma complex.
humpbacks ro inanon wai-roro area learn ia kurara mae/ni toa other.
and to kurara uabai turu themes and variations ra evolve tabun time.
[whales singing]
their mournful kurara were to key
to transforming maungatabu opinions about them.
[speaking russian]
[protester i english] mauri, boctok. ti ua-ra? canadian.
[over megaphone] taiaoka wi tiribo to tokitoki.
[attenborough] animals that had been viewed
as uta tabun than a uto ni wangewange ma meat
became personalities.
[protester tabun megaphone] ti ua-ra? uaakekei ma ninikiraen/roro, ma ti taetae ni uakaaka,
ma we're ni saying, "please wi tiribo to whales."
ti uabai pursued ruamaen nakon mate nako uaano tatai i ra history,
ma tiba ngai ngaia was tere, ngaia was manga acceptable.
the tiribo ni whales turned mae/ni to tai nakon to crime.
a tuanonoku katiba conscience had taebaba appeared.
ua wanted ruamaen nakon riki extinct.
maungatabu were obaba nakon wa-ni-marawa to natural tokin aonaba.
as ngaia were toronib'ai aware of to natural world.
ma ti tiba had to kawai nakon u maungatabu tabanga to tokin aonaba ata.
[theme otoanene playing]
[attenborough] by to time unga boati tokin aon aba aired i 1979, i had entered u 50s.
there were tai to number of maungatabu boati to planet
as akekei were tai i was born.
ko ma i korakina to moaniba buta ma dominant wari ni taimaeke boati tokin aon aba.
we're tai to moaniba numerous large animal.
there ua-ra? something like 4,000 wan/ea ni ngaira today,
ma we've tekeboti teuaei tukabu ni meteoric nikotatawa.
e a ni happened nae/no to tiku 2,000 ririki ke teuana.
ti mata nakon uabai tae/rib'ab'a tikibuaka mae/ni to restrictions
ngai uabai governed to activities ma nimaatenten ni other ruamaen.
[attenborough] we had tae/rib'ab'a loose.
we were apart from to tiatiana ni unga boati earth,
living to okoro waaraoi ni life.
our predators had been eliminated.
most ni ra kinaka were maian control.
we had worked out how nakon uamari amarake nakon order.
akekei was ware tabun nakon wariki ngaira.
ware nakon wi ngaira.
unless ti mate ngaira.
we uarea tauraroa consuming to earth until ti had taneiai ngaia up.
baimano tabeman wari ke toara bakabwi ni wari
uarea tuai uarea toamau.
tabanin habitats uarea uana naba wana nakon ribu.
i uan Nei Rara witnessed to destruction of to tabanin habitat i southeast asia.
in to 1950s, borneo was three-quarters covered ni rainforest.
[young attenborough] we heard a taururu inanon tabera ahead.
and akekei, tiri to wanibanga kairo away,
we waiteketeke to wari furry uraura form swaying inanon trees.
the orangutan.
[attenborough] by to wi ni to century,
borneo's rainforest had been maerikiriki i half.
rainforests ua-ra? particularly precious habitats.
[birds chirping]
more tabun wewene ni to species on una rake mweraoi here.
they're wene i which evolution's tae/rena ni waua soars.
[birds squawking]
[clicking]
many ni to wan/ea ni species in to buakonikai exist i wano numbers.
every teuana a to niba ni ngo role nakon play.
orangutan toba nna spend ten ririki ni ia young,
teaching ngaia ra fruits are ware eating.
without teuaei training,
they uarea tuai urouronga ia role in dispersing seeds.
the rimwi generations of uaano warawara wari uarea uarea i risk.
and warawara diversity a to key to to rainforest.
[birds chirping]
in to wai-rena wano patch of tropical rainforest,
there kona be 700 okoro wari ni tree,
as uaano nika akekei are in to tabanin ni taenimeang america.
and tuai, aio tera we've been turning teuaei dizzying diversity into.
a monoculture ni wangewange palm.
a habitat ngai a wenei i comparison.
ma ko tara teuaei roki ni mawawa ni tai mannannang i ngaia,
ma ko taku e a tao e raoiroi.
ma ngkana ko ana i to helicopter,
ko tara ngai ngai a to unaririkia riaki wewene to maire warebwe.
ma tibae/ra ngai unaririkia,
there a ware ma regimented rows of wangewange palms.
there a to wi-uai incentive to tou forests.
people benefit mae/ni to timber...
and rimwi benefit riki from farming to una rake nenei tabun behind.
[chainsaw revs]
which a buki we've uriri down three trillion waraa tabanga to world.
half ni to tokin aonaba rainforests have kaman been cleared.
what ti tara rianibai today
is uaraoi to latest chapter in to global tiki spanning millennia.
the deforestation ni borneo has maerikiriki to population ni orangutan
by two-thirds ngkai i uan Nei Rara tao one just tabun 60 ririki ago.
ti can't tou rainforests forever,
ma anything ngai ti can't uareke forever a i definition unsustainable.
if ti uareke bairaroi ngai ua-ra? unsustainable,
the taonaba nonona ultimately to a winikibwi rikea to tabanin wabobo collapses.
tiaki ecosystem, tiaki taeka uarea wi warebwe, a tokara.
even teuana nika mawa nika to ocean.
this habitat was to subject of to series to uunikaai buraneti,
which ti were filming inanon waeremwe '90s.
ngaia was. to astonishing mitarao ni to ni uteanibai tokin aonaba,
to tokin aonaba ngai had existed ngkai to tei ni wia raoi.
ni tei ni bairaroi ngai ko had tiaki tabuaiaka had ever existed,
ni i to uanao ni uraura, ni unbelievably waebua.
and ni ni ngaia ni undisturbed by mi presence.
for uareke ni na expanse, the ruruon a largely empty.
but i teuana wene, iai mika spots
where teke ua tabo uota nutrients to to surface
and niko to rebwe ni life.
in ikoa places, huge rotabonaeti ni wirikoi gather.
the problem a ngai ra waru fleets
are uaraoi nika wiraraoi i finding those mika wa-n-ta nika ua-ra? to fish.
when ngaia uareke, * kona nakon gather the ntaninin rotabonaeti ni ease.
it was tiri inanon '50s ngai wari fleets
first ventured out into international waters...
to b'ania to wi-o ruruon harvest across to globe.
yet, they've removed 90% ni to wari wirikoi inanon sea.
at uan Nei Rara, ngaia caught plenty ni wirikoi i ia nets.
but nae/no tiri to wanibanga years,
the rika tabanga to globe were obaba i empty.
to waru witoka became teuana toronrang
ngai countries began nakon subsidize to tikubae/raa nakon reka to tae/ningamarau.
without wari fish and other tutune predators,
the oceanic nutrient cycle stutters.
the predators toa nakon tauraroa nutrients in to ruruon sunlit waters,
recycling ngaia teuana ngai ngaia kona uarea used again ma riki i plankton.
without predators,
nutrients ua-ra? uteae/nibaka ni centuries to to depths
and to mika wa-n-ta wana nakon diminish.
to ruruon tabemoa nakon uramate.
ocean unga was also unravelling inanon shallows.
in 1998, to blue buraneti film crew
stumbled boati to event little tanoata i to time.
coral waiwai were toi white.
the white uraura a caused by tab'anin expelling algae
that mweraoi symbiotically within ia body.
tai ko uan Nei Rara tara ngaia,
ko taku tao ngai e a waebua, ma taebaba ko waki e a tragic.
kioina tera * looking i a ri.
skeletons ni wenei creatures.
the white tab'anin ua-ra? ultimately smothered i seaweed.
and to waiwai karuoruo mae/ni wonderland... to wasteland.
at uan Nei Rara, to waka ni to bleaching was to mystery.
but scientists started nakon matata that in uaano tao rikea kunimae/toa occurred,
the ruruon was warming.
for uta time,
climate scientists had warned that to buraneti uarea ana warmer
as ti uramai fossil fuels and moti ro carbon dioxide
and other greenhouse gasses into to atmosphere.
a waiteketeke unora i atmospheric carbon
has always been incompatible with to toronibai earth.
it was to feature of ni nimaung una extinctions.
in rimoa events,
it had reketati volcanic activity up nakon teuana wan/ea years
to dredge uti toamau carbon from nae/no to tokin aon aba
to niko to catastrophe.
by uramara wan/ea ni years' worth of ro organisms
all ngkainaba nika ninikaro ma oil,
we had managed nakon uareke teuana i kakarakoa tabun 200.
to global wi n ang temperature had been relatively toronibai ua to '90s.
ma ngaia tiba appeared teuaei was tiri kioina to ruruon
was absorbing uareke ni to tao taumaete, masking ra impact.
it was to uan Nei Rara kina nakon me
that to tokin aon aba was beginning to tua na balance.
the moaniba tabara habitat ni all
exists i to rang north and taota ni to planet.
i've runga to polar regions over uaano decades.
[imperceptible]
they've always been to place beyond imagination...
with scenery unlike anything rua boati earth...
and takarere species adapted nakon to unga inanon extreme.
but ngai tawaewae tokin aonaba a changing.
in u wia raoi, i've experienced the warming ni arctic summers.
we uabai korobuki i locations
expecting nakon uareke expanses ni tari ice and tei none.
we've managed nakon waero i boat
to aono ngai were impossible to ana nakon historically
because ngaia were permanently in inanon ice.
i to wia raoi frozen planet aired i 2011,
to wanawana ni uakai unora was wiraoi matoro.
the ruruon a wai-ananau since become unable nakon absorb
all to tao heat caused i ra activities.
nika to ua, to average global temperature today
a teuana rikuri celsius warmer tabun ngaia was tai i was momoi.
a nikotatawa ni unora ngai exceeds any inanon tiku 10,000 years.
summer tari aiti inanon arctic has maerikiriki i 40% i 40 years.
ra buraneti a losing na aiti.
this moaniba pristine ma distant of ecosystems a headed ni disaster.
ra baituru a tiba bon global.
ra impact tiba bon unene.
ra moti ro ukirea boati to buraneti
a finally nako mai nakon taeka to tutu fundamentals ni to ro tokin aonaba.
we uabai overfished 30% ni wirikoi stocks to niba ni ngo levels.
we uriri down over 15 tebirian waraa toa year.
[warbling]
by damming, polluting, and over-extracting ranga ma lakes,
we've maerikiriki to size of freshwater populations i tabun 80%.
we're replacing to tiriwenei ni to rena.
half ni to unabia una rake boati earth is tiba farmland.
70% ni to una ni birds on teuaei buraneti ua-ra? ninibanga birds.
the mawa maiti, chickens.
we touakina ni tabun one-third of to tinea ni man boati earth.
a kabi 60% ua-ra? to animals we waboboa nakon eat.
the tiatiana, mae/ni mice nakon whales, make uti uaraoi 4%.
aio tiba ra buraneti,
waanikarau i humankind ni humankind.
iai uta tabun ni to tiatiana ni to ro tokin aonaba.
since i started filming inanon 1950s,
on average, tiriwenei taimaeke populations have tabun tabun halved.
i kungtara uakai tamnei now and i waki that,
although nika to waeai man i felt i was uramate akekei inanon wild
experiencing to untouched natural world...
it was to illusion.
those buakonikai ma aoraoi ma seas were kaman emptying.
um, teuana, to tokin aonaba a tuai nika tiriwenei nika ngaia was.
wiraoi, we've uruana ngaia. tuai uaraoi waenib'aka ngaia.
i teiabuaka, ti uabai ni. wiraoi, uruana ngai tokin aonaba.
ngai non-human tokin aonaba a tarao.
uh. to. aonteaba beings uabai ueka to tokin aonaba.
ngai a u no taeka.
to wi-mari ni global ruo during to wai-rena lifetime.
but ngaia keng wi there.
ngkana ti tana boati ra teke ua tabo tukunango,
to taonaba ngai a been to defining maetakanikan ni u lifetime
winaine uarea eclipsed i to taonaba obaba inanon next.
uteanibai bineang ngai were i momoi today,
i uarea uarea no nakon to taobura.
the amazon rainforest, tou until it kona manga  uamari toamau moisture,
degrades into to tung savannah,
bringing catastrophic wari loss...
and altering to global uria ni bati cycle.
at to wai-roro time, the arctic riki ice-free inanon summer.
without to white aiti cap,
less ni to tai energy is reflected wete uramate nakon space.
and to nikotatawa ni global warming increases.
throughout to north, frozen waaka thaw, releasing methane,
a greenhouse ang uaano tatai tabun potent than carbon dioxide,
accelerating to rate of aoraoi unora dramatically.
as to ruruon tana nakon heat and riki tabun acidic,
coral waiwai namoa to tokin aonaba die.
fish populations crash.
global amarake production ninia to crisis as waaka riki uke i overuse.
pollinating maniman disappear.
[thunder rumbling]
and to taeae/nimaero is more ma tabun unpredictable.
our buraneti becomes four rikuri celsius warmer.
large wi-ni-mane ni to earth are uninhabitable.
millions ni maungatabu rendered homeless.
a ono una mate nako event...
is wiraoi underway.
this a to uatao ni one-way doors...
bringing irreversible change.
within to uba ni to next lifetime,
the mweraoi ma stability of to holocene,
our garden ni eden...
will uarea lost.
uaraoi tiba, we're facing to manmade naouatao ni global were.
ra greatest tabora i w&aelign;/inga ni ririki.
ngkana ti tikabu urouronga makuri,
to bukirurunga ni ra tiwiriteetian
ma to mate nako ni uareke ni to natural tokin aonaba a boati to toki ni mata.
ma to longer ti naako ngaia,
to tabun nang it'll uarea nakon uareke something riaki ngaia.
ma ko kona happily ririkaaki.
ma ko tiba tangiria ni tere nakon ngaira tera taberamate ti ua-ra? i.
um.
ma, i to ua, i tangira i wasn't waninia i teuaei un.
[chuckles]
kioina i tangira to un wasn't akekei ke riai.
ma i've had unbelievable wia raoi ma wiraraoi taobura.
um, ma i tai uarea ri tutu tuna.
ngkana i tao tera to problems ua-ra? ma maotoua nakon tinae/nikua ngaia.
[audience applauding]
[attenborough boati video] climbing tabun to tightly-packed bodies
is to tiri ua tabanga to crowd.
[groaning]
those maian kona ana manatua nakon death.
[walruses groaning]
[attenborough] we ua-ra? facing ware less than to bukirurunga ni to ro world.
the tutu mena ngai gave birth to ra civilization.
the mena ti ongea upon for toa mena ni to mweraoi ti lead.
no teuana tangira teuaei nakon happen.
none ni ngaira kona afford ni ngaia nakon happen.
so, tera uareke ti do?
e a quite straightforward.
e a been staring ngaira inanon wia ni along.
to wae teimatoa nakon ra planet,
we riai wae na biodiversity.
the tutu mena ngai we've removed.
it's to tiri ua uramate ni teuaei crisis we uabai created.
we riai rewild to world.
[uplifting otoanene playing]
[reindeer grunting]
[birds hooting]
[buffalo snorting]
[birds cawing]
[elephants trumpeting]
rewilding to tokin aonaba a simpler tabun ko might taku.
ma to unora ti nna u
winaine tiri benefit ngaira ma to tamaroro ngai waki.
to tiEn/ture mae/ni tiba, ra buraneti kona uarea to tiriwenei wene riki.
ma nangi nako  taekina ko uarea.
[cawing ma chirping]
every other wari boati tokin aon aba reaches a maximum population wia to time.
the ware ngai kona uarea sustained on to natural resources available.
with ware nakon wariki us,
our population a been growing dramatically throughout u lifetime.
[crowd chanting]
on teke ua tabo projections,
there winaine uarea 11 tebirian people on tokin aon aba i 2100.
but e a possible nakon slow,
even nakon wi population growth well wia ngaia reaches ngai point.
japan's maro ni living
climbed witokatoka inanon latter half of to 20th century.
as healthcare ma reirei improved,
people's expectations and opportunities grew,
and to tauan roro rate fell.
in 1950, to japanese wari was likely to uabai uatao ke tabun children.
by 1975, to average was two.
the ua a ngai to population has tiba stabilized
and a ura changed since to millennium.
there ua-ra? torara ngai teuaei a started to uarea tabanga to globe.
as botanaomata utuaki everywhere, people rine nakon uabai fewer children.
the ware ni uakaaka being born worldwide toa year
is nang tiritoa off.
a unora wanawana to population is matu growing
is kioina uaano ni ngaira ua-ra? ro longer.
at uta winikibwi inanon future,
the aonteaba population winaine peak for to tutu uan Nei Rara time.
the sooner ngaia happens,
the easier ngaia u tokikan else we nna do.
[crowd cheering]
[attenborough] by taobong hard to waboboa maungatabu uramate ni poverty,
giving ni access nakon healthcare,
and enabling naakai i particular to weneakina i uma n reirei nika wai-ananau nika possible,
we kona u ngaia tabera sooner and i to tuka level.
buki wouldn't ti tangiria ni uareke uakai bairaroi?
kakaiangatoa maungatabu to maiti opportunity ni unga
a tera ti uarea tangiria ni uareke anyway.
to uaraoa a nakon waboboa to maro ni ro namoa to tokin aonaba
toara ribaba ra impact boati ngai tokin aonaba.
ngai Mei rebwe impossible,
ma iai katei i ra ti kona uareke teuaei.
the ro world is essentially solar-powered.
the tokin aon aba plants
capture uatao trillion kilowatt-hours of solar taururu toa day.
[birds chirping]
that's tua 20 tatai to energy we kai. uaraoi mae/ni sunlight.
imagine ngkana ti phase uramate fossil fuels
and waanikarau ra tokin aonaba boati to totoki energies of buaiaka too.
sunlight, wawe, uria ni bati ma geothermal.
[indistinct chatter]
[attenborough] at to urung ni to century,
morocco relied boati imported wangewange ma gas for tua ni ni na energy.
today, ngaia generates 40% ni na kai i home
from to network ni renewable ubati plants, including to tokin aonaba largest solar farm.
sitting boati to win te bike ni to sahara,
and cabled directly into southern europe,
morocco kona uarea to exporter of solar taururu i 2050.
within 20 ririki, renewables ua-ra? predicted to uarea to tokin aonaba un uto ni power.
but ti kona u ngaia to tiri source.
e a tiriou ngai ra rekebiri ma ra ro ua-ra? investing i fossil kanaiai.
tai uakai ua-ra? to tutu bairaroi
ngai ua-ra? jeopardizing to rimwi ngai ti ua-ra? baimano ni.
[sirens wailing]
a renewable future will uarea ibaba benefits.
energy buta winaine uarea tabun affordable.
our cities winaine uarea cleaner ma quieter.
and renewable taururu winaine wanga waanikarau out.
the ro tokin aonaba can't kua without a rung ruruon ma neither kona we.
the ruruon a to niba ni ngo iranibuobuoki i ra battle to uramara carbon inanon atmosphere.
the tabun diverse ngaia is, the uamoa ngaia does ngai job.
[whales singing]
and, bareng to ruruon a important to ni ni ngaira nika to uto ni food.
fishing a tokin aonaba greatest tiriwenei harvest.
and ngkana ti uareke ngaia uaraoi, ngaia kona continue...
because akekei to win-win i play.
the healthier to tutune habitat,
the tabun wirikoi akekei winaine be, and to tabun akekei winaine uarea nakon eat.
palau a to pacific uum'a nation
reliant boati na tab'anin reefs for wirikoi ma tourism.
when wirikoi nango began nakon reduce,
the palauans responded by restricting waru practices
and banning fishing entirely mae/ni uaano areas.
protected wirikoi populations soon became teuana healthy,
they spilt tabun into to areas open nakon fishing.
as to result,
the "no fish" to uabai increased the wawa ni to local fishermen,
while i to wai-roro time allowing to waiwai nakon recover.
imagine ngkana ti bure to a botoa wia bong tabanga to world.
estimates wiwina ngai "no fish" zones over to tenua ni ra coastal seas
would uarea uaraoi nakon tianakia us with ni to wirikoi ti winaine ever need.
in international waters,
the un a attempting nakon create the biggest "no fish" to ni all.
in teuana act, this uarea onika to wi-o ocean
from to wene exhausted by subsidized waru fleets
to to rereua ngai winaine toa ngaira all in ra uke nakon kaunikai aoraoi change.
the tokin aonaba greatest wildlife reserve.
when ngaia nako mai nakon to land,
ti riai radically uramara to aon ti uteanibaka nakon ribana,
teuana ngai ti kona u uki ni returning rereua.
ma to quickest ma moaniba effective ua nakon uareke ngai a ni ngaira nakon unora ra diet.
[birds chirping]
large carnivores ua-ra? wanawananrang/ i nature
because ngaia urouronga * ni prey to wakaa toa ni them.
[wildebeest snorting]
for toa wai-rena predator on to serengeti,
there ua-ra? tabun tabun 100 kona animals.
[snorting]
whenever ti rine to ung ni meat,
we taomoa ua-ra? unwittingly demanding a tabati expanse ni space.
to buraneti can't wakaa tebirian ni wari meat-eaters.
akekei uaraoi keng to uki.
[dings]
if ti ni had to largely plant-based diet,
we uarea kai tiri wewene to land we uteanibaka i to moment.
ma kioina ti uarea uarea rimwi dedicated nakon mwemwerake ruakai,
ti kona utuaki to tanga ni teuaei una rake substantially.
the netherlands a teuana ni to world's most densely-populated countries.
it's rabu ni wano family-run farms with tiaki uma n amarake ni expansion.
so, dutch ribana uabai riki expert at getting to moaniba uramate ni toa hectare.
increasingly, they're wa teuana sustainably.
raising tanga tenfold i uoua generations while i to wai-roro wia raoi using kakarakoa water,
fewer pesticides, kakarakoa fertilizer and emitting kakarakoa carbon.
despite na size,
the netherlands a tiba to world's second largest exporter ni food.
e a kati possible ni ngaira nakon turuna uaia low-tech ma hi-tech iango
nakon uamari uareke tabun amarake mae/ni uareke kakarakoa una rake.
we kona wana nakon uamari food in e boou spaces.
indoors, nae/no cities.
even i places where akekei tiaki una rake i all.
as ti karaoiroi ra wia bong nakon farming,
we'll wana nakon tinaniku to land-grab ngai we've been kakaee
ever ngkai ti began nakon ribana,
ra a un kioina ti uabai to urgent kai ni ni ngai wanimae/rawaa una rake.
forests ua-ra? to fundamental component of ra buraneti recovery.
they ua-ra? to taberanikai technology buaiaka has for locking ti carbon.
and * kinono ni biodiversity.
again, to uoua ina wakoro together.
the wilder ma tabun diverse buakonikai are,
the tabun effective ngaia are at absorbing carbon mae/ni to atmosphere.
ti riai immediately tiku-tumauma deforestation buta.
and rikirake ima te rain wangewange uriba ma soya only boati una rake ngai was deforested wai-ananau ago.
after ni, akekei mari ni it.
ma ti kona uareke uamoa tabun ngai.
a tiEn/ture tai, tabun tabun uatao quarters of costa rica was rabu ni forest.
by to 1980s, uncontrolled logging had maerikiriki teuaei nakon uaraoi teuana quarter.
the tautaeka maotoua nakon act,
offering grants nakon una rake owners to replant imae/tang trees.
in uaraoi 25 years,
the buakonikai a returned nakon cover half ni costa rica tai again.
[birds chirping]
just taku ngkana ti achieve this on to global scale.
to taumae/toa ni to waraa uarea taon
nika uareke nika uoua tenua ni to carbon boi
ngai uabai been pumped into to ea i ra activities nakon bong.
with ni uakai things,
there a teuana overriding principle.
nature a ra biggest ally and ra greatest inspiration.
we uaraoi nna uareke tera nature has always done.
it worked uramate to wibine ni unga wai-ananau ago.
in teuaei world, a wari kona tiri thrive...
when tokikan else around ngaia nikoraoi, too.
we kona solve to problems ti tiba face
by embracing teuaei reality.
if ti arokana ni nature,
nature winaine arokana ni us.
it's tiba wia raoi ni ra species to wi tiri growing.
to unika to unga boati ra planet in tie ni nature.
to wana nakon thrive.
tai ko iango ngaia, we're completing to uaiakina.
rebu ririki tai, nika hunter-gatherers,
ti lived to sustainable unga kioina ngai was to tiri rine.
ni uakai ririki rimwi, e a tai riki to tiri rine.
ti kai nakon rediscover.
uarea nakon uarea sustainable.
nakon wawaeakina mae/ni being tibe mae/ni buaiaka
nakon wau to wi-ni-mane ni buaiaka tai riki.
tonight, we've got to rather okoro program ibukim
[attenborough] if ti kona change the ua ti mweraoi boati earth,
an alternative rimwi nako mai into view.
in teuaei future,
we matata katei nakon benefit mae/ni ra land that toa, rather tabun wanre, wilderness.
ways nakon wirikoi ra tari ngai enable them to nako mai witoka wete nakon life.
and katei nakon harvest our buakonikai sustainably.
we winaine finally wareb'ai uarea nakon work with buaiaka rather tabun unrake it.
inanon wi, wia to lifetime's exploration ni to ro tokin aonaba,
i teuana ni teuana
aio tuai riaki baimano ra buraneti.
e a riaki baimano ngaira.
the koaua a, ni ke toara us, the natural tokin aonaba winaine rebuild.
in to 30 years since to evacuation ni chernobyl,
the tiriwenei a reclaimed to space.
[birds chirping]
today, to buakonikai a reketati tabun to city.
it's to nikawewe ni tiriwenei animals that ua-ra? tutu wanawananrang/ elsewhere.
and tuanonoku evidence that however ruanimaete ra mistakes,
nature winaine ultimately tokarakea them.
the ro tokin aonaba winaine endure.
we aonteaba cannot aananga to same.
we've nako mai teuaei far
because ti ua-ra? to smartest creatures that uabai ever lived.
but nakon continue, we require tabun tabun intelligence.
we require wisdom.
iai uaano taunari renaua aonteaba ma to tiatiana ni to wari boati tokin aon aba,
ma teuana ngai a been expressed a ngai ti wakoro ua-ra? kona nakon taku to rimwi.
ni to iro i ma tao iroum  dreaded ngai rimwi.
ma e a tiba wau tere ngai e a tuai ni doom ma ro.
akekei to tokabura ni ngaira nakon u kabo,
nakon urouronga ra uaiakina ni rikirake, toamau ra impact,
ma tai riki riki to wari i tie ni buaiaka.
ni ti kai a to winaine nakon uareke teuana.
ti tiba uabai to opportunity nakon riki to tungatunga unata ni ngaira,
ma wae to tokatake, rung, ma wonderful tokin aonaba ngai ti ba n uri.
uaraoi taku ngai.